<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<pragyan>
  <item>
    <itemname> Events </itemname>
    <children>
      <item>
        <itemname> Core Engineering </itemname>
        <one> Breeding New-Age Technocrats </one>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/core.jpg</imgurl>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Junkyard Wars </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 25000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Build Weapons From The Junkyard </one>
			
			<starttime>01-03-2013 08:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:30</endtime>
	<starttime>02-03-2013 08:30</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 17:30</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/junkyard_wars/introduction/junkyardwars.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
A lever is just a rod as long as you don’t use a fulcrum. “One man`s trash is another man`s treasure”. So, is everything else just junk as long as you don’t put it to use the right way?
 
Have an opportunity to use all of your engineering prowess and intellect to create machines to battle out. Junkyard Wars is a 3-day event where you must build a working model from the junk provided to your team. 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Online Round 1

- Online round 1 will be held between 15th and 16th February, 2013.
 
- The online round will end at 6:00 PM on 16th February, 2013.

- It will consist of about 45 questions both subjective as well as Multiple choice. Subjective questions should be answered in 2-3 lines.

- Questions will test the participants’ knowledge in basic physics, mechanics and engineering concepts.

- Time alloted for the round will be 50 minutes.

- Only one submission is allowed per team.

- No modifications can be made once the answers are submitted.
 
 				    
Online Round 2
 
- Those qualified in Online round 1 will go to Online round 2.
     
- Qualified teams will be contacted by e-mail and all relevant information regarding the round will be sent through email.
     
- The round is essentially a case-study variant. Different situations shall be provided and the relevant mechanism(s) and/or design should be conceived for each situation to carry out the given task perfectly.
     
- Practical Problem solving skills of the participants shall be tested.
     
- Participants will be required to upload the solutions in .pdf or .doc or .ppt format (with relevant sketches included).
     
- Deadline for the qualified teams to upload their solution is 20th February, 2013.
     
- Only one submission is allowed per team.
     
- The decision about a team’s selection for the final On-campus event will be made on or before 21st February, 2013.
  
											
Final Round
 
- Teams which are qualified for the final round will be intimated through email.

- Qualified teams have to be present on campus during pragyan.

- The problem statement will be released on Day 0 of Pragyan (February 28th).

- Required materials, work space, tools and equipments will be provided for teams to carry out the task.

- Teams have to compete aginst each other with their constructed model.		

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Each team should consist of 5 members only.

- Each team must formulate their own ideas and designs. Plagiarism in any form shall lead to disqualification.  

- Non working models will not be allowed to be showcased.

- All the team members must be present during the finals.

- Participants must comply with the rules of the Workshop area where the model will be built.

- Junkyard Wars is not responsible for any loss of property, injury and delays caused by participants during the event.

- Junkyard Wars reserves the right to eliminate the participants in case of any misconduct.

- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Junkyard Wars.

- Decision of the judges is final and binding to all.

- The rules indicated in the Event Format section are applicable in addition to the above mentioned.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: junkyardwars@pragyan.org
 
Arjun Thiagarajan
Phone:  +91 96771 17912
 
Sandeep Bhat
Phone: +91 72006 10141

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x210junkyard.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>NFS Aqua</itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 30000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> RC Motorboat Racing </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:30</endtime>
 <starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:30</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/nfs_aqua/introduction/nfs-aqua.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Here’s a cool respite from the array of fiery racing events! Of all, this is the only aquatic contest.
 
You must’ve enjoyed veering through the waves in jet skis. Now, let your boat do it for you as you wield its controls.
 
Hold your helm tight, troubled waters ahead! 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Event Stages
 
- Abstract submission (Non Eliminative). 
 
	- Abstract format (should not exceed 1 page): 
 
		- Name, College and contact detail of the team leader.
              
		- Frequency of remote and reception.
             
		- Briefly explain the design and the material used for the boat.
	
		- What is unique about your boat? 

- On campus race.
 
 
 
Track Specification
 
- The race track will be a track with left, right and U turns, S-shaped curves and hurdles.
 
- Despite organizers efforts to keep the track quality intact, if the track shakes slightly because of the ripples, participants should be able to control their boat accordingly.
 
- More details about the track will be provided to you soon. However the exact track will be revealed only on the day of the race.
 
- A lap of the track is defined to be completed when the boat comes back to the start-finish line.
 
- Remote control should be capable to cover a range of at least 20 feet so as to complete the race without failure.
 
- Elevated standing position for better control will be provided to the participants. Which will improve the controlling by a participant team by improving the visibility of the whole track at a single sight? But there is no such restriction to control the boat by making use of the provided platform.
 
 
 
Machine specification
 
Dimension and Fabrication
 
- Maximum length of the boat: 20 inches.  
 
- Maximum width of the boat: 7 inches.
 
- The boat has to be controlled by a wireless remote control mechanism throughout the competition.
 
- The boat must not be made from Lego parts, or any ready-made assembly kits.
 
- Remote control systems from toys might be used. Remote control systems available in the market may also be used.
 
- Balsa wood or fibre glass or any other light in weight but strong material can be used for the construction.
 
Motor specifications
 
- The boat must have an onboard power supply to provide power to any mechanism requiring electric power.
 
- Only dc motor should be used for the power supply.
 
- The maximum allowed speed of an electric motor is 7000 r.p.m.(i.e. Participants can also use dc motor of 5000 r.p.m or any other dc motor lower in speed than 7000 r.p.m )
 
- The electric voltage provided to the motor shaft should not be more than 7.2V.
 
- Speed controller should be used so as to control the speed of the dc motor.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Each team should consist of 5 members only.
 
- Each team must formulate their own ideas and designs. Plagiarism in any form shall lead to disqualification.  
 
- Non working models will not be allowed to be showcased.
 
- All the team members must be present during the finals.
 
- Participants must comply with the rules of the Workshop area where the model will be built.
 
- Junkyard Wars is not responsible for any loss of property, injury and delays caused by participants during the event.
 
- Junkyard Wars reserves the right to eliminate the participants in case of any misconduct.
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Junkyard Wars.
 
- Decision of the judges is final and binding to all.
 
- The rules indicated in the Event Format section are applicable in addition to the above mentioned.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Email: nfsaqua@pragyan.org

Ankit Jalan
Phone: +91 93631 01398

Harsh Phophalia
Phone: +91 81223 67921

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x250NFSAqua.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Allumette </itemname>
            <main> Registration deadline extended to $$!!$$17th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 25000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Manufacture Free-Flowing Potassium Chlorate </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 12:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/allumette/introduction/allumete1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Pragyan’13 presents Allumette, a rare opportunity to collaborate your academic brilliance with real life problem statement directly applicable in the industrial scenario.  This event aims to be a strong platform for budding engineers to exhibit their innate talents and practical viewpoints in the process of acquiring an innovative solution for the given situation. Potassium Chlorate is the main ingredient in “Match head composition”.  In powder form, it is highly susceptible to moisture absorption from the atmosphere.  This triggers the tendency to form lump-like deposits which gradually get hardened with the passage of time.  This eventually slows down the overall process as unnecessary labor is required to remove these deposits to make Potassium Chlorate free-flowing. And now, the challenge is to propose a technically sound, economically viable and well-engineered solution to manufacture free-flowing Potassium Chlorate.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement
 
Check out the problem statement at http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/Allumette/.
 

Event Stages
 
Round 1
 
- The participants (Team size: max 3 members) have to submit an online abstract of their idea.
 
- Last date for abstract submission has been extended to 17th February, 2013.

- To submit the abstract, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/Allumette/.
 
Round 2
 
- The shortlisted teams will mail the complete description of the idea with fully explained models and diagrams wherever applicable.
 
- The last date for mailing the complete descriptions is 24th February, 2013.
 
Round 3
 
- The selected teams will present their idea to the panel of judges during Pragyan. The team will then be questioned by the judges.

 
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Allumette.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: allumette@pragyan.org
 
Sona
Phone: +91 98424 78877

Vaibhav 
Phone: +91 81227 40311
</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x150allumete.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> D-Chrome </itemname>
            <main>Registration deadline extended to $$!!$$17th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 25000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Remove The Chromium From The Waste </one>
			<starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 12:00</endtime>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/d_chrome/introduction/d-chrome.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
"Only when I saw the Earth from space, in all its ineffable beauty and fragility, did I realize that humankind's most urgent task is to cherish and preserve it for future generations."
- Sigmund Jahn, German cosmonaut.
 
“Viridis Postremo” - Pragyan'13 is back with the punch to defend our nature!!  Here is providing a platform for the GREEN engineer in you, with the sole purpose of solving real environmental oriented problem faced by the industries. 
Chromium, used in the manufacturing process of Potassium Chlorate, when present in large quantities and in different forms is toxic.  Hence, the waste sludge that contains Chromium needs the right treatment to bring down the toxicity level.
Come up with an innovative solution to tackle the danger caused by untreated effluents being dumped directly into open environment and thereby, lessen the burden that nature already faces.
GET GEARED!! GET TECH!! GET GREEN!!

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement
 
Check out the problem statement at http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/D_Chrome/.
 

Event Stages
 
Round 1
 
- The participants (Team size: max 3 members) have to submit an online abstract of their idea.
 
- Last date for abstract submission has been extended to 17th February, 2013.

- To submit the abstract, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/D_Chrome/.
 
Round 2
 
- The shortlisted teams will mail the complete description of the idea with fully explained models and diagrams wherever applicable.
 
- The last date for mailing the complete descriptions is 24th February, 2013.
 
Round 3
 
- The selected teams will present their idea to the panel of judges during Pragyan. The team will then be questioned by the judges.
 
 
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in D-Chrome.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: dchrome@pragyan.org
 
Sona
Phone: +91 98424 78877

Vaibhav 
Phone: +91 81227 40311
</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x150dchrome.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Contraptions</itemname>
            <main> Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 55000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Time To Complicate An Easy Task </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:00</endtime>
 <starttime>02-03-2013 08:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:00</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/contraption/introduction/contraption.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
“Simplicity is the ultimate sophistication.”
                              -Leonardo da Vinci
 
And indeed it is. Simplicity is the law of the world. But for those who think defying the laws is awesome and creating awe is passion, Welcome ! We want you to think, rethink, conquer the boundaries of your imagination to defy all that logic and make the Mundane, Insane!! Take the task, fiddle with the laws, and get ready to blow minds!! The more the complexity, the more you earn!!
 
Here at Contraptions we truly believe that science is not meant to be taught in boring, confined boxes, but unleashed and experimented with -and this alone reflects its true mastery.
 
Throw in all the energy conversions you are aware of as one continuous routine without physically engaging yourself at any stage (Aaah yes that's the real challenge).
 
So, ladies and gentlemen, get ready for showcasing your wildest and most complex solutions.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
 
Problem Statement
 
- Check out the problem statement at http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/contraption/.


Judging criteria
 
- Number of steps in the contraption. 

- Number of energy conversions.
 
- Time taken for the contraption (choose time optimally, more weightage for no of steps).
 
- Types of energy conversions.
 .
 
Abstract Submission
 
- To submit the abstract please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/contraption/. 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations </pagename>
              <content>
- The entire contraption to include should remain completely within an Square whose dimensions are 4m x 4m  at any point of operation.
     
- Once the first step has been initiated, intervention of any sort in the following steps would lead to deduction in points.
     
- An initial setup time of 180 minutes will be given for each team. In addition to this, a setup time of 10 minutes will be given for every team before each trial. Moreover, points will be deducted for consecutive trials.
     
- Maximum of 3 trials would be allowed for each team.
     
- The total trial time (including setup time) taken for task should not exceed 20 minutes.
     
- 220 volts AC supply would be provided at the event venue.
     
- Teams may use commercially available machines as individual parts of your contraption. Any questionable items must be given prior consent by the event manager. If you have any special requirements inform us well in advance. It will be taken care of. Extension cords, scissors, tape etc. will be provided.
     
- A step is defined as an action that results in another action working towards the final aim of the machine. For example the act of tipping over of block of wood with a rolling ball is a step. The actual tipping motion of the block is not a step unless it causes another action to occur. A series of the same actions repeated such as dominoes knocking each other over or a ball hitting another ball are considered to be one step in the spirit of the competition.
     
- A parallel step is defined as an action which initiates multiple smaller steps, starting and ending at the same point, at the same instant of time. This will be counted as one parallel step irrespective of the number of smaller steps initiated.
     
- Teams have to submit a report at the time of the competition which will contain a detailed description of each of the steps and energy conversions in the arrangement. Teams are encouraged to support their report with indicative diagrams.
     
- All the materials required for the arrangement should be brought by the corresponding team. Teams are not allowed to share any material. No material will be provided by the organizers.
     
- Contestants are responsible for removing their arrangement and any debris left after the completion of their 3 rounds.
     
- In case of any manual interventions during the run, points will be deducted and the team will have to go for the next run if there are more than 3 interventions.
     
- Judges decision will be final and binding!
 
- The organizers reserve the rights to change any or all of the above rules as they deem fit.


Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Contraptions.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: contraptions@pragyan.org

Stanish
Phone: +91 96292 88629

Karthik
Phone: +91 80565 15050

Srinath
Phone: +91 90421 86149

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x150contraptions.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Nittro </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 80000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Race Your Little Devils In The Dirt </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 20:00</endtime>
 <starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 20:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 16:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/nittro/introduction/nitro.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
NEED FOR SPEED….FORMULA 1….DIRT….BLUR….BURN OUT…. Fond of these games? Enough of sticking your heads in Play Station and PCs, it’s time to get ready. We offer you a chance to design and fabricate your own Nitro powered Remote controlled car and get down the track to race not just money and pride but for the feel….experience….thrill….desire and passion. Your Racing and Engineering Skills will be put to test in our event NITTRO-Pragyan’13. Cash prize worth INR 60000 to be won, so Think…. Design…. Create…. And don’t forget to bring your creation to NITTRO-Pragyan 13.
 
Gentlemen racing skill is not the only thing which can earn you money and pride. Maneuvering an RC car with style and ease is a skill not possessed by everyone. To those racing fanatics out there, we offer you a chance to unravel your skills in our event NITTRO- Pragyan 13.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement

To make a wireless remote controlled machine, powered only by an IC Engine which can complete and compete with other opponents on an off-road dirt track with many obstacles in the least possible time.



Stages of the event

Abstract Submission:

- Format of the abstract is available for download at http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/nittro/. Edit the same file and upload your abstracts while registering.

- Abstracts can also be uploaded after registration.

- Video of the working model: Upload the video on youtube and include the link in your abstract.

- Photos of the chassis, steering and suspension system fabricated: Zip the photos and upload in the appropriate column while registering

- To submit abstract, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/nittro/.

- Deadline: Deadline for submitting the abstracts are 25th February, 2013.
 
- Note: The abstract is non-eliminative and is intended to give us an idea about the effort put in by the participants.


Inspection:

- Participants report to the venue with their machines.

- Strict inspection of the machine is carried out according to the guidelines and regulations set by the organizers.

- All selected teams will be given practice slots of 15 minutes each, after the inspection is completed.


Race Event:

Prelims

- All selected teams will now have to compete in a time trial.

- Each team will be given a run of 2 individual laps and the best lap time will be considered.

Final Rounds:

- This will be primarily a knock out round.

- Head to head knock out races would be held to determine the winner.


Free Style:

- All selected teams will perform a series of tasks (i.e. maneuvering a football on to goal post. etc.) which will be informed half an hour prior to the event.

- Points will be given based on execution of the tasks given.

- The team with the highest points wins the event.


***Note: In case of any technical or organizational difficulties format of event may be changed during the event depending upon the situation. Organizers decision is final and no argument will be encouraged.
		

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Track Specifications

- The race track will be an off-road dirt track with left and right turns, hairpins, S-shaped curves, bumps and puddles.

- Participants are advised to use proper suspension systems for their machines to endure the bumps.

- A lap is deemed to be completed when the machine completes the entire track andcomes back to the starting point.

- The track will have check points at regular intervals. If a machine tumbles, or halts, or goes off the arena at any point on the track, one of the team members is allowed to lift it up and place it at the nearest checkpoint behind that point. The time shall still be running in the meantime.

- Team members are not permitted to touch either their machines or those of their opponents once the race begins (unless there is need to lift the machine as stated in the previous point). The penalty for doing so is disqualification.

- Details about the track will be updated soon.



Technical Specifications

Engine:

- The maximum allowed capacity of IC engine to be used is 4.6 cc (i.e. Participants can also use 2.5 cc, 3 cc, 3.5 cc or any other IC engine lower in capacity)..

- There is no restriction on the type of IC engine (either glow or diesel cycle engine), but the engine must have throttle control.

Fuel:

- The percentage of nitro methane should not exceed 20% by volume in the fuel.

Vehicle dimensions:

- Machine should fit in a box of dimensions 800mm x 600mm x600mm (l x b x h) at any moment of time during the race. The external device which is used to control the machine is not included in the size constraint.


The machine may be roughly classified into structural and functional parts:

       - Functional parts - Gears, differential gear, engine, springs, shock absorbers, servo motors (non-propulsion purposes only), 		batteries, wheels, wheel hub are allowed to be used as available in the market.

       - Structural parts - Chassis, steering mechanism, shock towers, suspension (excluding upper suspension arm, suspension spring and 	shock absorbers), have to be built by the participants themselves.

Power supply:

- The machine must have an on-board power supply to provide power to any mechanism requiring electric power not exceeding 12V.

Radio controllers:

- The machine has to be necessarily controlled by a wireless remote control system.

- Participants are required to use a remote control of frequency of band spectrum 2.4 GHz. The above rule is to ensure that there is no frequency clash during the competition and participants are not allowed to use any other remotes with frequency other than 2.4 GHz. (In case of unavailability of remote control, i.e 2.4 GHz the participants are required to submit their remote in organizers desk and it will returned during respected practise slots and race only, in order to avoid frequency clash)

Control Space:

- An elevated podium will be provided for the control of the machine. The podium will ensure good visibility for the controller.



Team Specifications:

- A team can consist of a maximum of 5 members. Students from different educational institutes can form a team.



Eligibility:

- All students with a valid identity card of their respective educational institutes are eligible to participate in NITTro at Pragyan 2013.



General Rules

- If the machine is found unsafe to run on the track, the team will be disqualified from the race. The organizers' decision would be final and binding in this respect.

- The vehicles are not allowed to leave any loose parts on any part of the arena. Any vehicle disintegrating during the race will be disqualified.

- Teams are not allowed to purposefully damage the machine of the opponent's team. If found doing so on track (while racing), the concerned team will be disqualified.

- The teams must adhere to the spirit of healthy competition. The coordinators reserve the right to disqualify any team indulged in misbehavior.

- If any of the machines starts off before the flag is waved, the counter would be restarted and the machines will get a second chance. However, if any machine starts off before the waving of flag (or countdown) for a second time, it will be disqualified. No rematch will be held for the second time.

- Judges decision shall be treated as final and binding on all.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: nittro@pragyan.org

Jothi Prakash

Phone: +91 99526 17665

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x310nittro.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Hydro </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$20th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 20000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> 0% Electric. 100% Hydraulic. Find Out How. </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:30</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hydro/introduction/hydro1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
"Water is the driving force of all nature."  
                                   - Leonardo da Vinci
 
And so it seems. Now, get ready to design and build a hydraulic arm that can lift up and place things and also complete a task, without the use of electronics.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
To design and fabricate a hydraulically actuated mechanical arm, which can pick up cups and place them on the staging area in the correct order to form the given word, in the shortest possible time.
 

Please check the Rules and Regulations page for the arena format.
		

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Pre-Event Rules
 
- Submit an abstract describing the design of the arm before February 15, 2013.
 
- The”mechanical arm” should be setup in the staging area before starting the event.
 
- No part of the arm should cross the demarcating line before the commencement of event.
 
- The teams are allowed to start operating the controllers only after the start of timer, when instructed by the organizer.
 
- To submit the abstract of the design of the arm, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/hydro/.
 
 
During the Event
 
- Cups, with letters printed on them will be placed at Zone B and they should be picked and placed on the elevated platform (Zone A) in sequence to get the right word.
 
- The timer will be stopped when all the cups have been arranged to form the right word in zone.
 
 
Regulations
 
- A team can consist up to 4 members
 
- The arm should have a stable base and must be able to stand by itself at all positions.
 
- All the joints of the arm must be actuated hydraulically and must be operated with manual controls.
 
- The controls must not be mounted on the any of the moving parts of the arm. The controls may be placed on the base or any part of the staging area.
 
- The participants will be allowed to handle only the controls and not the arm or the cups during the event.
 
- The participants are allowed to use any material (Popsicle sticks, ply wood, etc) to build the arm. Stock arms are not allowed.
 
- Electrical or Electronic components such as motors, batteries should not be used.
 
- The judging will be based on time taken to achieve the task and special prizes will be given for design.
 
 
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Hydro.
 
 
Arena Dimensions
- Please refer the figures at the bottom for arena dimensions.

</content>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hydro/rules_and_regulations/hydro_1.jpg</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hydro/rules_and_regulations/hydro_3.jpg</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hydro/rules_and_regulations/hydro_2.jpg</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hydro/rules_and_regulations/hydro_4.jpg</pgimg>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: hydro@pragyan.org

Rahul Ajith Kumar
Phone: +91 77085 45251

Vageesh
Phone: +91 96295 34387

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/410x150hydro.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Hover One </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 40000$$%%$$</main>
            <one>Race Your RC Hovercraft  </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:30</endtime>
<starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 17:30</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hover_one/introduction/RC_Hovercraft.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
"Flying down to earth is called humility, at Pragyan we call it HoverOne"
 
Let there be no terrain unconquered,no wind unmatched,as we not just fly or sail, we hover.
Bringing to you the advancements of the most basic physics.The amendments to the existing theories, HoverOne!
Glide over land,water and much more and bring out the adrenaline junkie in you.
Race your way to Rs 40,000 and catch the thrill of drift this Pragyan.
 
This time remain in the air yet play it dirty!
  
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement
 
To design a hovercraft or ACV (air cushion vehicle) that will be tested for speed, manoeuvrability and handling on various terrains like sand, water and gravel. It requires the participant to build a radio controlled hovercraft that could complete the specified track in the least possible time.
 
 
Round 1: Testing
 
- This round requires the participants to drive their hovercraft on the given track of about 8 metres length.
 
- The width of the track will be 1.5m.
 
- The teams will be given a maximum of one attempt.
 
- Max time allotted is 3 minutes.
 
- This round is eliminative. A maximum of 8 teams will be selected for the second round (7+1).
 
 
Round 2:  Manoeuvrability
 
- This round requires the participants to manoeuvre their hovercrafts through the given track.
 
- The width of the track will be 1.5m.
 
- The teams will be given a maximum of two attempts.
 
- The maximum time allotted is 8 minutes
 
- This round is the final round. The top three finalists’ names will be handed over to the Pragyan Events head.
 
 
Track Details 

Track Details for Round 1:

- Please refer to Figure 1 at the bottom of the page. 
 
Track Details for Round 2:

- Please refer to Figure 1 at the bottom of the page. 
 
</content>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hover_one/event_format/Track for round 1.jpg</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/hover_one/event_format/Track for round 2.jpg</pgimg>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Design Constraints and Fabrication
 
- The maximum dimensions of the model allowed are 60cm x 50cm x 50cm (lxbxh).
 
- There is no limit on the weight of the craft.
 
- The use of IC Engines is strictly prohibited. Only DC motors are allowed.
 
- Use of ready-made actuators/motors, remote control units, electronic speed controllers and propellers is allowed.
 
- Teams should bring their own remote controls, and they must operate at 2.4 GHz. Radios with any other frequency are prohibited for use during the event.
 
- Ready to use kits and readymade building kits are strictly prohibited.
 
- There is no limitation on the type or no. of motors or servos that can be used.
 
- Crafts found damaging the arena will be immediately disqualified.
 
  
General Rules
 
- Participants will be provided with a practice round, a day prior to the event.
 
- There is no limit on the weight of the craft.
 
- A team may consist of 4 to 8 members.
 
- Only one member of the team is allowed to run the hovercraft during the event.
 
- The arena is subject to changes during the event, depending upon the level of participation.
 
- Event management's decision will be final in case of any conflicts.
 
- Other communication devices are not allowed near the arena while the competition is on. This includes remote control of your car while some other team’s run is on. The organizers hold the right to check for these devices and their usage.
 
- Only 2 members from the team are allowed to be near the game field.
 
- The time measured by the organizers will be final and will be used for scoring the teams. Time measured by any contestant by any other means is not acceptable for scoring. In general, the decision of the organizers will be final and binding in all circumstances.
 
- There will be a certain number of check points on the track, which will be informed to the participants before the start of the run. If a machine falls from a height off the track or gets stuck, then it will be placed back on the last check point the machine has passed. This will be done by the organizers. Teams are not allowed to touch the machines during the run (except if the team announces time-out as per the next rule (7)). The timer will keep running during this process.
 
- Time Outs: A team is also allowed time outs of maximum duration 1 minute in case it feels that manual intervention is required to repair any damage or malfunctioning. A maximum of 3 timeouts can be taken. The timer will be stopped for the duration of the time out.
 
- Participants should mail us the pictures and/or videos of their RC Hovercrafts by 20th February, 2013.
 
 
Safety Precautions
 
- It is the participants’ responsibility to have their hovercrafts waterproofed completely, the battery especially to prevent damage to the arena.
 
- The organizers’ reserve the right to disqualify any hovercraft which he/she deems unsafe for motion in water.
 
- In the event of any hovercraft causing an explosion/fire or damage to the arena in any way, he/she will be unconditionally and immediately disqualified.
  
 
Judging
 
Round 1:
 
- Teams have to aim for the best lap times. The lap time will be calculated as follows:
- Lap time = actual time taken to complete the track.
 
Round 2:
 
- There will be in all 3 checkpoints.
 
- Crossing each check point awards the participants a set number of points which have been described as follows-
 
       - 1st checkpoint - 100 points
 
       - 2nd checkpoint - 50 points
 
       - 3rd checkpoint - 100 points
 
- The total points are cumulative that is if a contestant crosses only up to 2nd checkpoint the total number of points he/she earns is 150 points.
 
- The total number of points won divided by the total time is calculated for each participant.
 
- The participant with the highest value of points earned per unit time takes the 1st place and so on for 2nd and 3rd position.
  
 
Eligibility 
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Hover One.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>

Email: hoverone@pragyan.org

Shubham Thirani
Phone: +91 96005 70476


Karthik Vinayagamoorthi
Phone: +91 80565 15050

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x140hoverone.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Delta-T </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$18th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 30000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Natural Water Heat Exchanger </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/delta_t/introduction/delta-t.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Delta T is back for Pragyan 2013 focusing on real time industrial solutions.
This time around, Delta T aims to bring out ideas of innovative heat exchanger design and its application in industries. The participants are required to construct a working model of a heat exchanger to effectively transfer heat from a hot source to cold sink using a secondary heat transfer fluid without direct contact.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
 
Problem Statement
 
Design a heat exchanger that can convey heat from a hot water source (H) to two cold water sinks (C1 and C2) by the use of a third transfer fluid (T). Thermal fluid T should transfer heat from H to C1 first and then from C1 to C2. There should not be any direct transfer of heat from H to C2 and C1 should be the only source of heat for C2. The distances between H-C1 and C1-C2 should be 30 cm.
 
 
 
Event Stages
 
- Stage I
 
       - The participants will have to submit an abstract of the design in the specified format. The last date for submission of 		abstracts is 18th February 2013.
 
       - To see details regarding the abstract please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/delta_t/.
 
- Stage II
 
       - Shortlisted teams must bring their working models on the day of the event for testing. The model will be tested by the judging 	panel based on the judging criteria.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Maximum of 3 members per team.
 
- Each team will be provided with 2 litres of water at room temperature (C1 1 litre and C2 1 litre) and 2 litres of water at elevated temperature (60-70oC).
 
- Do not use water as the third transfer fluid.
 
- The area occupied by the design should be within 1.5m X 1.5m.
 
- The water should not be contaminated before, during or after the heat exchange process. Points will be deducted if there is any volume loss in the water provided.
 
- Water discharge from the cold sink (both C1 and C2) should be provided in such a way that the water can be collected in a container with insulating walls. The temperature of cold water will be measured from that container.
 
- The entire process should be completed in the least time possible (which should not exceed 10 min).
 
- No other heating/electrical devices allowed. Exothermic reactions should not be used.
 
- Mixing of fluids is not allowed.
 
- Unwanted and unnecessary actions or behaviour by participant shall not be tolerated, and will lead to disqualification of the team.
 
- Marks will be deducted for any actions violating the above rules.
 
- Judge’s decision is final.
 
- If there are any queries regarding the problem statement, mail them to deltat@pragyan.org
 
  
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Delta-T.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: deltat@pragyan.org

Monica Roy
Phone: +91 91762 80153

Gowtham Kumar T
Phone: +91 97898 01257

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x160deltaT.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Green Electricity </itemname>
            <main>Registration deadline extended to $$!!$$18th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 10000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Develop A Clean Energy Source </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/green_electricity/introduction/green-electricity1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
The recent failures of India’s power grid have not only forced more than 600 million people to survive without electricity – they’ve demonstrated the need for massive investments in clean technology and infrastructure. The emphasis on green technology is a product of the pricking question due to growing concerns about the environment.  The nitty-gritty of this event is to develop an idea for clean energy generation. 
With plenty of electricity problems in Southern states and opposition to other viable power sources by many players, it becomes clear that conventional, non-renewable energy is not the solution. This necessitates development of clean energy. If you think you have that little ‘spark’ that has ‘potential’ to solve a seemingly unsolvable issue at hand, this is for you.
  
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement
 
Alternative clean energy ways to produce electricity
 
Today India's total renewable energy generation contributes to only 30 percent of the total when compared to a whopping 70 percent by non-renewable energy resources. Through this event we intend to take a step towards increasing the renewable energy power generation. A Recent breakthrough in alternative green energy resource is generation of electricity from husk in a village in Bihar. Similarly other clean energy resources that can be used are solid waste,tidal energy,Bio Mass etc.
 
We invite proposals to an alternative green energy solution.
 
 
- Clearly State:
 
       - Nature and origin of the source chosen.
 
       - Feasibility of the source for large scale generation of electricity.
 
       - Method Of Generation Of Electricity from the source.
 
       - Estimated Cost.
 
       - By products if any.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Round 1
 
- The participants have to submit the complete description of their idea, with fully explained models and diagrams. The teams will be shortlisted.
 
- Last date for submission of the abstract is 10 February, 2013.
 
- To submit abstract, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/core_engineering/Green_Electricity/.
 
 
Round 2
 
- The selected teams will have to present their ideas on campus before judges.
 
  
Evaluation Criteria
 
- Innovation
 
- Effectiveness of the method
 
- Benignity of the method
 
- Cost factor
 
- Feasibility for large scale production
 
  
Team Specification
 
- A team may consist of a maximum of 3 members.
 
- Every participant must register online.
 
  
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Green Electricity.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: greenelectricity@pragyan.org

Kotha Praneetha
Phone: +91 80568 22016

K.Vasanthi Lakshmi
Phone: +91 90039 93564

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x240greenelectricity.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Topographya</itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 20000$$%%$$</main>
            <one></one>
			
<starttime>02-03-2013 17:30</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 19:30</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 07:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 10:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/core_engineering/topographya/introduction/topographia1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
This is a fun-filled Civil Engineering based competition.
The participants will be asked to locate the position of a treasure based on purely numerical data and alphabetic symbols. Using their knowledge on ‘Surveying’ they have to crack the data and reach the position of the treasure.
 
Note: This event demands only the basic technical knowledge of the participants and not supreme skills.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Round 1
 
- Written type and eliminative.
 
- It will comprise of surveying as well as aptitude question.
 
- Duration is 45 – 60 minutes.
 
  
Round 2
 
- Final field round.
 
- Duration is 2 hours on the following day.
 
- This round will be held in the morning. 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
General Rules
 
- A team should comprise of 3 members.
 
- At least one Civil engineering student is required in a team. An ideal team composition has at least one Civil engineering student with sound technical knowledge, one who is sharp in numerical calculations and one who can think out of the box and execute works manually.
 
- Surveying instruments and other necessary equipments will be provided. The team will be accountable for any damage caused to the instruments.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: topographya@pragyan.org

Vasudha
Phone:+91 76393 22900

Vidya Sagar
Phone: +91 97900 92710

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x220topo.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
        </children>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Innovation</itemname>
        <one>Ideas For Life/Ideas That Last</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname> Sanrachana</itemname>
            <main>On-Spot Registrations$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 21000$$%%$$</main>
            <one>On-Spot Model Building Competition</one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 11:00</endtime>


<starttime>01-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:30</endtime>

 <starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 11:00</endtime>

 <starttime>02-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:30</endtime>
 
  <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 11:00</endtime>

 <starttime>03-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 17:30</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/innovation/sanrachana/introduction/sanrachana.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Sanrachana is an event of technical nature, which puts to test the skill of individuals in making working models with non-construction materials (drinking straws, popsicle sticks, matchsticks, pins and such) within a specified time and gauges their logical and implementation skills.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Event is conducted on each of the three days of Pragyan 2013.
 
- The Model to be built and the task it has to perform will be specified on the day of the event.
 
- Teams will be given the material for making the model and sufficient time to build their models before evaluating them.
 
- The criteria for judging will depend on the task to be performed and will be declared on the day of the event.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Maximum of 3 participants per team.
 
- Sufficient material and time will be given for model making.
 
- Teams should submit their models everyday on the same evening.
 
- Judging criteria will be clearly informed.
 
- Teams should use only the provided material and judge’s decision will be final.
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Sanrachana.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: sanrachana@pragyan.org

Chandrasekhar
Phone: +91 86080 05568

Vivek
Phone: +91 99431 79395

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x210sanrachana.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Anveshanam </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 35000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Present Your Ideas </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:00</endtime>
<starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 13:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/innovation/anveshanam/introduction/anveshanam1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Do scientific principles energize you? Are you of the opinion that innovation and creativity are best put as practice in applied science? That is the essence of engineering. Do you feel that you have a wealth of ideas or a brilliant conception only that you cannot find a platform to express it? Look no further. 
 
All you need is a laptop and lots of creativity and you are set to go. Quench your thirst for technology as you battle out amongst your peers and you will be fittingly rewarded.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Preliminary round will be held online.

- New ideas are appreciated and papers with originality and feasibility are given preference in the selection.
 
- The number of teams which will be selected depends upon the participation.
 
- The topics for the presentation include:
 
       - Building Science
  
       - Chemical and Material Sciences
  
       - Computer Sciences
  
       - Electrical Sciences
  
       - Mechanical Sciences and Production Technology

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Paper Submission
 
- Participants have to submit their full paper for scrutiny, abstracts will not be entertained.  
 
- The document format has to be in Microsoft Word (.doc or .docx) or Printable Document Format (.pdf) only.  
 
- The title of the submitted file must be a shortened version of their paper title. (eg: Suppose my paper title is “How to make the tastiest lemon juice from a given lemon, squeezer, water and ice”, then the name of my file will be “making tastiest lemon juice.doc”)
 
- Participants are requested to submit their papers in IEEE format. In case it is not possible, submitting the papers in any internationally recognized format is allowed. Else, they can submit their papers in a neat, legible, coherently arranged format, with perfect alignment, font adjustments (sizes, font type), naming of figures/tables/charts and references.  
 
- Papers with improper formatting will be sent back to the participants and they are encouraged to submit it again after re-formatting.  
 
- Kindly keep the font color of your paper as black (excluding figures, charts, tables).  
 
- Kindly provide your names, email addresses and contact numbers in the paper that you submit.
 
- Last date for submission of paper is 10th February, 2013. 
 
- To submit your paper, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/innovation/anveshanam/.

 
Presentation Details
 
- The presentation time will be 8 minutes + some time for questions and answers as per discretion of the judges.  
 
- Exceeding of time limit will invoke negative points.  
 
- Please bring your presentation in the form of .ppt or .pdf. Any other form of the file will not be entertained, please bring the file in a pen drive (avoid CD/DVD).  
 
- The participants can include any type of media (pictures, videos) in their presentation, provided they do not show any controversial clips.  
 
- All participants are strongly requested to be present at the venue15 minutes prior to the start of the presentation; once the event has begun the doors of the presentation hall will be closed and further entry will not be allowed. This is a very specific rule to be followed as it was requested by the judges themselves.  
 
- Decision of judges will be final and binding on all participants. Any discussions regarding evaluation process at any stage shall not be entertained. Selected participants for the final round are requested to prepare their presentation in Microsoft PowerPoint format (.ppt) or Printable Document Format (.pdf) only.
 
 
Eligibility Criteria
 
- Participants with a valid identity card or a Bonafide Certificate from their institute are eligible to participate in Anveshanam.
 
 
General Rules
 
- Maximum of two members allowed per team.
 
- Any number of teams from a college can submit their papers.
 
- Participants are not allowed to submit more than one paper.
 
- Participants can submit their papers in a maximum of 2 clusters, depending on the content of the paper.
 
- If shortlisted, they will be allowed to present it in only one cluster. (Specify your priorities in case of selection in both clusters).
 
- Participants are required to send a soft copy of their entire paper, in the IEEE format.
 
- The paper length should not exceed 12 pages, of the format specified.
 
- Participants whose papers are shortlisted shall be informed personally through mail. The names will be put up on the website as well.
 
- Participation certificate will be given to all the shortlisted participants.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>


Email: anveshanam@pragyan.org

T. Arima vu ram
Phone:+91 95662 17978

S. Baranidharan
Phone: +91 99404 73397

Gaurav W S
Phone: +91 99405 10133

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/260x210anveshanam.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Aakriti </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 25000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Live Design Contest </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/innovation/aakriti/introduction/aakriti.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Engineering is all about imagination and ingenuity. Rather than just theories and their application, it revolves around simpler domains such as indigenous thinking, common sense and elementary logic, all of which arise from the Supreme Intelligence, the "Pragyan" in us. Technology, as we know it today, is the manifestation of millennia of Pragyanic thought and action, which has unflinchingly served and enthralled mankind since the invention of the Wheel.
 
Pragyan, the annual Techno-Management festival of NIT, Trichy is a humble attempt to promote and foster this co-existential relationship between Man and Technology. The insignia, insinuating Man's eternally progressive leap over the Wheel of Technology, is symbolic of Pragyan’s endeavour to inculcate the spirit of engineering, innovation and forward thinking among the youth. For over half a decade, Pragyan has worked tirelessly towards this goal, by churning out several memorable editions, each of which has enlightened, emboldened and inspired an entire generation of engineers.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement
 
- Pragyan 2013 is planned for Feb 28 - March 3, 2013 and will play host to a series of events and competitions which will be attended by a multitude of colleges throughout the country. To conduct an event of this scale, any college campus requires a variety of spaces which are used for a host of uses and functions which change over the duration of the event and based on the nature of the event as well. NIT Trichy's infrastructure for these events includes the Barn hall, the LHC, the EEE Audi, and the halls in the Admin block with the central ground. Other spaces such as the department classrooms and labs are used in conjunction with these to serve a wide range of events.

- Design the informal chill-out spot for Pragyan ‘13, a space for the informal conversations, the coffee breaks, for spending free time between events, or simply as a hang-out spot during those hot lazy afternoons. The area of this semi-open temporary structure should be around 1500 sqft (±200 sqft, or aptly justified otherwise) and should also include a platform that can double up as a stage for informal events, and display panels that will show the evolution of Pragyan over the years.

- Design this temporary structure exhibiting innovation in construction and the use of material, built with an attention to feasible construction with an approximate estimated cost not above Rs. 1 lakh as a highly functional chill-out zone and we will be pleased to construct the winning entry and put it up for the intended use this Pragyan.*

- Entries shall be evaluated on originality, feasibility, innovation and adherence to the context. Participants are expected to furnish their designs with conceptual drawings and sketches with details on the method of construction and how the building material is employed to achieve the structure designed, to aid the actual construction if and when the design is employed. Remember, we might actually be building this structure,* so clarity in terms of material use, joints, etc. is essential.

- Architecture and engineering students are welcome to enter this competition either individually or in groups, up to a maximum of three members per team.

- Three prizes will also be awarded with Rs. 25,000 to be won in cash apart from actually seeing your winning design come to life this Pragyan.* The deadline for submission is 10th February, 2013.

- To download the CAD drawing of the site and surrounding structures and the Pragyan logo, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/innovation/aakriti/.


*Please understand that it would be our pleasure to construct the winning project, but we reserve the right to not build the winning project (or to choose the project next in line) if any complications arise during the planning or execution stages, or otherwise.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- The final submission shall be an A/V presentation up to a maximum of 15 minutes.

- A single printed A1 pin-up sheet showing working details and architectural drawings should also be included as a part of the presentation.

- All slides/sheets should hold the Pragyan logo in the bottom right corner with the registration number clearly mentioned. 

- Participant and Institution names should not be mentioned on the sheets/slides.

- The judges’ decisions shall be final and binding.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>

Email: aakriti@pragyan.org

Utsav Mathur
Phone: +91 96296 49007

Ajay Kumar Choudhary
Phone: +91 87546 39769

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x150AAKRITI.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>B-Green </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 20000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Green Campus Design Competition </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 15:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/innovation/b_green/introduction/BGreen_landing.png</pgimg>
              <content>
“You never change things by fighting the existing reality. To change something, build a new model that makes the existing model obsolete.”
                                                                             - Buckminster Fuller
 
We already know our civilization’s model is obsolete-so it’s time to put the thinking caps on. Pragyan 2013 invites you for some exciting Green Engineering. Enter the world of Building GREEN where aiming at evolving the most energy efficient, self-sustaining and economical Green Structure, the eco-minded of the country churns the realms of technology and creativity to produce magic.
 
The concept of Green Constructions has significantly evolved in the recent decades, and is advocated in every form feasible, with the growing demands for energy and resources. As power and materials get rarer and dearer, day by day, the future of construction clearly lies in self-sustainability.
 
With Green technology emerging as one of the niche areas of potential in the building scenario, Pragyan 2013 collaborating with IGBC takes pride in presenting our fellow eco-friends, B GREEN, the race to design the ultimate green building.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement
 
- To download the problem statement for B-Green, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/innovation/b_green/.
 

Round 1: Online Abstract Submission
 
- The problem statement is available in the website from January 10, 2013 and the teams must submit their abstracts in PDF format on or before February 10, 2013.

- For details regarding the abstract, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/innovation/b_green/. 
 

Round 2: Finals
 
- The finals will be held on day II of Pragyan 2013, (i.e.) March 2, 2013 at our campus.
 
- The teams, shortlisted based on their abstracts, will be notified via e-mail and will have to present their ideas using models developed in any of the design tools or hand-drawn materials. 
 
- The design of the models and the technologies adopted will be discussed in detail with a panel of experts from IGBC to evaluate the design, rating them on their efficiency and economy as a green building.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- The event is open to all.
 
- Each team can consist of a maximum of three participants.
 
- The participants need not be from the same background or college (i.e.) interdisciplinary participation is allowed. (e.g.: Architecture, Civil, and Electrical) 
 
- Read the problem statement, event format, abstract format and other relevant instructions carefully before you start working on the model. Participants are requested to follow the proper formats in order to avoid untoward confusions.
 
- The formats of submission are:
 
       - Presentation: *.ppt, *.pptx/*.pdf
 
       - Video File (Walkthrough): *.mpeg, *.avi, *.mkv, *.wmv, *.mp4, *.flv
 
       - Image File: *.jpeg, *.gif, *.bmp, *.tif 
 
       - Hand-Drawn Sketches: On A1/A2 size papers
 
       - Use of any other format is not allowed.
 
- Judges' decision on the best model will be final and binding.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
E-mail: bgreen@pragyan.org

Subramanian S
Phone: +91 96007 70255
                     
Shibhu S Kumaar
Phone: +91 84382 06285

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/BGreen_Thumbnail.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Concept Car Challenge </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$20th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 20000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Design Your Concept Car </one>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/innovation/c3/introduction/concept-car.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
"A true designer doesn’t wait to see what the future holds...
 ...Because the future is happening in his imagination today."
 
C3 is an event that aims to bring out the automobile designer in you. A platform for you to showcase your vision of a dream car, what you would want to see on the roads in the future and discuss it with the professionals who actually made it big with their own concepts and ideas.
 
So Go Ahead. Let your imagination run wild! Invoke randomness upon thee and let your designing skill loose and come up with a super car that can would the roads of the future.
 
* A special prize shall be given to the most GREEN concept* 
 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Phase 1

- Participants are required to bring forth any innovative concept for a four-wheeled vehicle.
     
- It can range from designing a new aerodynamic spoiler to a whole new car which is left to the participants’ discretion.  


Phase 2

- Participants are required to provide the most appropriate solution to the problem put forth by a reputed auto maker. The problem statement will be put up soon!
     
- The presentation should include an outline of the concept, external appearance, highlights on specific and unique features incorporated in the concept, and a general layout of the vehicle that accounts for the placement of the essentials(engine, transmission etc.)

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Maximum of two members per team. One entry per team only.
 
- Participants selected for the presentation round are required to carry a bonafide certificate or identity card of their institute.
 
- The duration of presentation is not to exceed 5 minutes for Phase I, and 3 minutes for Phase II
 
- The presentation shall be followed by a question and answer session.
 
- Any design software (3DsMax, Catia, Pro-E, Rhino, Alias and Solid Works only) or hand drawn sketches may be used for the presentation.
 
- For the preliminary stage an abstract not exceeding one A4 page (std. font sizing) along with the preliminary / basic design of your concept and the solution to the questionnaire should be submitted, based on which the participants will be shortlisted.
 
- To submit the abstract, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/innovation/c3/.
 
- Shortlisted participants will receive the automaker problem statement by mail.
 
- They are required to bring atleast 2 hard copies of the design; a soft copy of the presentation and the solution to the above mentioned problem statement for the event. The hard copy is expected to include any supporting textual content with the design.
 
- Kindly note that the images supporting the design (if any) have to be in any of the following standard image formats (jpeg, bmp, gif, png, tif only.)
 
- Participants are to note that judge's decisions are final and binding.


Judging Criteria

- Unique primary function / concept of the vehicle
     
- Innovative features incorporated
     
- Practical relevance
     
- Aesthetic appeal
     
- Effectiveness of the solution to the problem statement.
     
- Solution to the questionnaire
     
- Apart from these, three different fields of Judge's discretion will be revealed on the spot(if any) and a separate winner for on the spot from Judge's own selection apart from main winners can also be declared.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: c3@pragyan.org

Vishwajeet
Phone: +91 98432 59403

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x150conceptcar.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/innovation.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Robovigyan </itemname>
        <one>Your Intelligence Hard-Wired</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname> Traffic Rush</itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 30000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> The Line Follower Event </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 08:30</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:00</endtime>

<starttime>02-03-2013 08:30</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:00</endtime>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/traffic_rush/Introduction/traffic-rush1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
A simple line follower event for beginners in robotics. However the bot not only has to traverse a black line on a white background, but has to negotiate through obstacles, inversions and discontinuity and determine the correct path and navigate through a toll plaza.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Problem Statement
 
- Build an autonomous line follower robot which would negotiate through obstacles, inversions and discontinuity and determine the correct path and navigate through a toll plaza. 
 
 
Arena Specification
 
Prelims:
 
- The arena will have a single track which is indicated by a line of width 3 cm. The designed track might consist of straight lines, smooth curves , sharp turns and discontinuities  the track is a black line on a white background .Discontinuities will not be more than 20cm. Obstacles (5cm x 5cm x 10cm painted white) will be placed on each track. The bot will have to evade the obstacles, cross the discontinuities and navigate till the IR LED checkpoint.
 
Finals:
 
- Here the bot has to retrace the path (mentioned above)till the check point (5cm X 5cm IR LED array placed 15 cm from the track and at 3-8 cm height). The bot will have to scan the three bit binary code from the card board(three boxes of specification 5cmx5cm each) that gives the toll booth number ,placed opposite to the LED checkpoint .The booths will be numbered starting from the left. After getting the input the bot has to navigate to the specified booth number and once it enters the booth the end of the circuit will be marked by discontinuity of 5cm  and a vertical strip of black line perpendicular to the direction of booth line. The bot has to park at this point and the same can be used for the indication of completion of track.
 
 
Sample Arena
 
- Please refer to the figure at the bottom of the page for the sample arena.


Dimensions and Fabrications
 
- The bot must fit within a square of dimensions 20cm x 20cm. There are no height constraints.
 
- The bot must sense the IR led checkpoint (3-8cm high) kept 15 cm from the track on the left side of the track.
 
- It should also scan the binary input kept 15cm from the track on the right side.
 
- Each machine must be stable and should be able to stand on its own at the beginning of the race when put in the start zone. Machines not fulfilling this criterion will be disqualified.
 
- During the run, the machine can expand itself provided it does not damage the arena in anyway. However, it is not allowed to leave anything behind or make any marks while traversing the arena. No machine can separate or split into two or more units. All machines found damaging the arena will be immediately disqualified.
 
- The teams are allowed to use readymade sensor kits. But use of Lego kits and any other readymade components is not allowed (readymade PCB for handling microcontrollers are not allowed).
 
 
Power Supply and Propulsion
 
- The bot must use an on-board power supply. No external power supply will be allowed.
 
- Each team shall prepare its own power supply for all its machines.
 
- The potential difference between any two points on any of the machines must not exceed 12 V DC.
  
 
Controls
 
- The bot must be completely autonomous.
 
- It should not receive any external help during the course of the run.

</content>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/traffic_rush/event_format/123.jpg</pgimg>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Event Rules
 
- All teams will be given a calibration time of 10 minutes.
 
- Maximum time given for one trial is 10 minutes.
 
- The starting procedure of the robot should be simple and should not involve giving the machine any manual force or impulse in any direction.
 
- Each bot is supposed to indicate with a suitable indicator (LED, Buzzer, etc.), clearly visible to the judges, when the bot has reached the check point. This indicator should be off at all other times. Any team unable to indicate this accurately will incur a penalty.
 
- Before each game begins, the participants should clearly describe how their robot detects the obstacles and indicates at the check point.
 
- Each team is allowed a maximum of 3 trials. All trials require the approval of the presiding judges before the machine can be removed from the arena. In each trial, the timer will be set back to zero.
 
- During a trial, the machine will have to be restarted by putting it back on the start zone. For a trial, the machine will have to be in Power Off mode and turned on again at the start zone on the signal of the judges.
 
- Between trials, participants may not feed information about the arena to the machine. However, participants are allowed to: Adjust sensors (Gain, Position etc.), Change speed settings and Make repairs. However, a participant may not alter a machine in a manner that alters its weight (e.g. removal of a bulky sensor array or switching to lighter batteries to get better speed). The judges shall arbitrate. The points earned by the team till that time will be retained.
 
- Participants will not be allowed to handle the obstacle positions on the track. Only event managers are allowed to handle the obstacles.
 
- Participants are not allowed to keep anything inside the arena other than the machine.
 
- The judges may stop any robot at any time if they feel that it is performing, or is about to perform, any action that is dangerous or hazardous to people or equipment. No robot is allowed to use any flammable, combustible, explosive or potentially dangerous processes.
 
- Readymade sensors (eg. line array sensors) could be used.
  
 
Team Composition:
 
- Maximum of 4 participants per team.
 
- Teams should register themselves online.
 
- No person shall be a member of two teams.
 
- Maximum of ten teams will be shortlisted for the finals.
 
- A team can constitute of member from different colleges.
 
- Participants are requested not to assume any details.
 
- Other details regarding the arena can be clarified directly with the event managers.
  
 
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Traffic Rush.
 
  
General Rules:
 
- The time measured by the organizers will be final and will be used for scoring the teams. Time measured by any participant by any other means is not acceptable for scoring.
 
- In case of any disputes / discrepancies, the organizers' decision will be final and binding.
 
- Participants must bring their own computers, programmers and software if they wish to program their robots at the competition site.
 
- The participants are requested not to assume anything without discussing with the event managers.
 
- The organizers reserve the rights to change any or all of the above rules as they deem fit.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: trafficrush@pragyan.org

Vignesh P
Mobile: +91 94873 66850

Ram Prasad R
Mobile: +91 96008 46482

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/310x200traffic-rush.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Bank Job </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$20th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 40000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Pull Off A Heist Using Image Processing</one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 15:00</endtime>
<starttime>02-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 15:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/bank_jobs/introduction/bankjob.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
The Pragyan Bank has a sophisticated security system. Like any security system it has its own flaws. Take advantage of these flaws and build an autonomous robot based on image processing principles to pull off a heist.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
The Arena

- Please refer to the figure at the bottom of the page for the arena. 
 
NOTE:
- The three colored circles represent the three denominations which will be specified soon. These three colors are fixed. Their positions in the arena will be random.
 
- The black square represents the deposition zone and it is also the start zone.
 
- This image is just to provide an idea as to how the arena will look like. Actual images of the arena taken from the overhead camera will be similar to the above image and will be uploaded by the end of next week. 
 
- It will be a 2mx2m arena printed on a flex sheet. At one corner is the depositing zone and the other is the start zones. Coloured circles (Red,Yellow,Cyan) with a diameter of 25cm will be placed randomly on the arena as shown in the figure. Each of the colour represents a denomination of the currency.
  
 
The Task
 
- The teams will be given a text file just before start.
 
- The text file will indicate the exact amount to be robbed.
 
- Based on that the robot will have to navigate to the various colours depending on the denomination.
 
- Navigating to and standing over one coloured circle represents collecting one note of that particular denomination. The bot can collect a maximum of two notes(and both of them have to be of different denominations) after which the bot must go back to the deposition zone before collecting another note.
 
- For example if the red circle stands for Rs. 100, cyan for Rs. 50, and yellow for Rs. 10 and the amount specified by the text file is Rs. 170, then the robot must follow the following directions:
Start zone-&gt; go and stand over Red circle-&gt;go and stand over cyan circle-&gt;Deposition zone -&gt; to the yellow circle-&gt;Deposition zone-&gt;yellow circle again-&gt;Deposition zone.
 
- The order of collecting the notes is immaterial.
 
- 15 minutes of calibration time and 10 minutes of run time will be given to all the teams. The teams can ask for any number of resets during the 10 minutes runtie, but the time won't be stopped.
 
  
Scoring
 
- SCORE=1000-A-B-C
 
where, A is the deficit amount not collected by the robot. For eg. If the given task was for Rs 100 and the bot collected Rs 60 then A=40; 
B=2*extra amount collected by the bot; 
C=100*(Number of times the bot violates the clause mentioned in point 4 of THE TASK). 
 
- If there is a tie in the scores, then the robot with least number of violations and the time taken to accumulate the amount will be considered. 
 
 
Robot Specifications
 
- The dimensions should not exceed 25x25x25cm.
 
- It should be fully autonomous.
 
- It may or may not be wired and if wired, wires of sufficient length should be used to prevent the wire from the laptop to the bot from slacking.
 
- The power supply must be  on board and the voltage between any two points must not exceed 12V.
 
- Arduino and its clones are allowed. However, other readymade microcontroller boards purchased as a part of kits are not allowed. If a team has printed their own development board PCB, then a schematic and layout of the board has to be submitted to the event managers before the event.
 
- If boards have been self-designed and printed, hard copy of the design must be submitted to the organisers before the start of the competition.
 
- Any bots which are found to be damaging the arena will be disqualified immediately.
 
- If a team is getting any of their Microcontroller Boards or other electronic stuff printed on PCBs, the layouts and Schematics of the boards must be submitted to the organisers beforehand.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Bank Job.
 
 
General Rules
 
- Any team that is not ready at the time specified will be removed from the competition automatically.
 
- The machines would be checked for their safety before the run and would be discarded if found unsafe for other participants and spectators.
 
- Participants should not dismantle their robots before the completion of the whole competition as the machines might need to be verified by the organisers at a later stage to ensure that the participants have not violated any of the rules.
 
- Organisers' decision shall be treated as final and binding on all.
 
- The organisers reserve the right to change any or all of the above rules as they deem fit. Change in rules, if any, will be highlighted on the website and notified to the registered participants through email.
 
- A team may comprise of maximum 4 members and all teams must have their college id cards.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: bankjob@pragyan.org

Manikandan Ananth
Phone: +91 99527 83687

Vighnesh Susrutha
Phone: +91 94446 11242

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/140x200bankjob.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Robowars </itemname>
            <main>Registration deadline extended to $$!!$$9th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 50000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Pit Your Robot Against The Rest </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 22:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 20:00</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/robo_war/introduction/robowars1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
"War does not determine who is right - only who is left."
              -Bertrand Russell.
 
Welcome to the battle of the bots, Robowars!

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Abstract Submission
 
- The written abstract should be prepared on the following lines:
 
	- The weapon systems and power supply method should be explained in detail, along with proper diagrams. Picture(s) showing these should be attached.
 
	- Description of any unusual advantageous mechanism used.
 
	- The specifications of all the components used, including motors, suspension springs, remote controller, wires, battery etc. have to be mentioned.
 
- You can email the portfolio minus the video and send the video later. This will make sure at least the abstract part of your portfolio reaches us before the deadline.
 
- An email will be sent to the team leader confirming the receipt of the entry. Each team is allowed to make online submission only by email. In case of multiple submissions, only the first submission will be used for judging purposes.
 
- Pragyan 2013 is not responsible for any delays in terms of receiving portfolio, so participants are encouraged to mail their entries well in advance to ensure receipt before the last date.
 
- Abstract file name should be named as Teamname_collegename. 
 
- The abstract can be a .pdf file or a microsoft word file only.
 
- To submit the abstract, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/robovigyan/robo_war/.
 
- Last date to upload abstract without photo and video is 9, Feb 2013. Last date for providing with photos or video is 10, Feb 2013.
 
 
Criteria for Victory 
 
- A robot is declared victorious if its opponent is immobilized.
 
- A robot will be declared immobile if it cannot display controlled motion. A bot with one side of its drive train disabled will not be counted out if it can demonstrate some degree of controlled movement. This rule will also apply to any robot that becomes trapped by any part of the arena or arena hazards.
 
- In case both the robots remain mobile after the end of the round then the winner will be decided subjectively.
 
- A robot that is deemed unsafe by the judges after the match has begun will be disqualified and therefore declared the loser. The match will be immediately halted and the opponent will be awarded a win.
 
- If a robot is thrown out of the arena the match will stop immediately, and the robot still inside the arena will automatically be declared as the winner.
 
- Robots can not win by pinning or lifting their opponents. Organizers will allow pinning or lifting for a maximum of 20 seconds per pin/lift then the robots will be instructed the attacker to release. If, after being instructed to do so, the attacker is able to release but does not, their robot may be disqualified. If two or more robots become entangled or a crushing or gripping weapon is employed and becomes trapped within another robot, then the competitors should make the timekeeper aware, the fight  should be stopped and the robots separated by the safest means.
 
- Points will be given on the basis of aggression, damage and control:
 
	- Aggression: Aggression is judged by the frequency, severity, boldness and effectiveness of attacks deliberately initiated by the robot against its opponent. If a robot appears to have accidentally attacked an opponent, that act will not be considered Aggression.
 
	- Control: Control means a robot is able to attack an opponent at its weakest point, use its weapons in the most effective way, avoid Arena Hazards, and minimize the damage caused by the opponent or its weapons.
 
	- Damage: Through deliberate action, a robot either directly, or indirectly using the Arena Hazards, reduces the functionality, effectiveness or defensibility of an opponent. Damage is not considered relevant if a robot inadvertently harms itself. Also, if a pressure vessel or a rapidly spinning device on a robot fragments, any damage to the opponent will not be considered "deliberate".

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Safety Rules
 
- Compliance with all event rules is mandatory. It is expected that competitors stay within the rules and procedures of their own accord and do not require constant policing
 
- Special care should be taken to protect the on-board batteries and pneumatics, robot without proper protection will not be allowed to compete.
 
- If you have a robot or weapon design that does not fit within the categories set forth in these rules or is in some way ambiguous or borderline, please contact the event organizers. Safe innovation is always encouraged, but surprising the organizers with your brilliant exploitation of a loophole may cause your robot to be disqualified before it even competes.
 
- Each event has safety inspections. It is at their sole discretion that your robot is allowed to compete. As a builder you are obligated to disclose all operating principles and potential dangers to the inspection staff.
 
- Proper activation and deactivation of robots is critical. Robots must only be activated in the arena, testing areas, or with expressed consent of the event coordinators.
 
- All participants build and operate robots at their own risk. Combat robotics is inherently dangerous. There is no amount of regulation that can encompass all the dangers involved. Please take care to not hurt yourself or others when building, testing and competing.
 
- All weapons must have a safety cover on any sharp edges. to the surroundings during the stay of the teams in the competition area should not be carried out without the consent of organizers. Not following this rule may result in disqualification.
 
- All the resources provided at the time of competition from the organizers should be strictly used only after the consent of the organizers.
 
- Once the robots have entered into the arena, no team members can enter into the arena at any point of time. In case if fight has to be halted in between and some changes have to be done in the arena or condition of the robot(s), it will be done by organizers only.
 
 
 
Team Specification
 
- Maximum of 5 members in a team.
 
- Team members can be from different colleges.
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Robowars.
 
 
 
Dimensions and Fabrications
 
- The machine should fit in a box of dimension 600 mm x 600 mm x 1000 mm (lxbxh) at any given point during the match. The external device used to control the machine or any external tank is not included in the size constraint.
 
- The machine should not exceed 30 kg of weight including the weight of onboard pneumatic source/tank. in case a external pneumatic tanks/source1.5 times the weight of the tank will be added to the weight of the bot.
 
- Weight of adaptors and the remote controller will not be counted.
 
 
 
Mobility
 
- All robots must have easily visible and controlled mobility in order to compete.
 
- Any machine component should not be detached (intentionally) during any point of the war.
 
- Methods of Mobility include:
     - Rolling (wheels, tracks or the whole robot)
     - Walking (linear actuated legs with no rolling or cam operated motion).
     - Shuffling(rotational cam operated legs)

- Not allowed :
     - Jumping and hopping
     - Flying (airfoil using, helium balloons, ornithopters, hovercrafts etc.)
  
 
Robot Control Requirements
 
- The machine can be controlled through wired or wireless remote.
 
- The machines using wireless remote must at least have a four frequency remote control circuit or two dual control circuits which may be interchanged before the start of the race to avoid frequency interference with other teams. The case of any interference in the wireless systems will not be considered for rematch or results.
 
- Remote control systems from toys might be used. Remote control systems available in the market may also be used.
 
  
Battery and Power
 
- The machine can be powered electrically only. Use of an IC engine in any form is not allowed. On board Batteries must be sealed, immobilized-electrolyte types (such as gel cells, lithium, NiCad, NiMH,or dry cells).
 
- The electric voltage between 2 points anywhere in the machine should not be more than 36 V DC at any point of time.
 
- All efforts must be made to protect battery terminals from a direct short and causing a battery fire,failure to do so will cause direct disqualification.
 
- Use of damaged, non-leak proof batteries may lead to disqualification.
 
- Special care should be taken to protect the on-board batteries.
 
- Change of battery will not be allowed during the match.
 
- One 220V power socket will be provided for each team.
 
 
Pneumatics
 
- Robot can use pressurized non-inflammable gases to actuate pneumatic devices. Maximum allowed outlet nozzle pressure is 8 bar. The storage tank and pressure regulators used by teams need to be certified and teams using pneumatics are required to produce the Safety and Security letters at the Registration Desk at the venue. Failing to do so will lead to direct disqualification.
 
- Participants must be able to indicate the used pressure with integrated or temporarily fitted pressure gauge. Also there should be provision to check the cylinder pressure on the bot.
 
- The maximum pressure in cylinder should not exceed the rated pressure at any point of time.
 
- You must have a safe way of refilling the system and determining the on board pressure.
 
- All pneumatic components on board a robot must be securely mounted. Care must be taken while mounting the pressure vessel and armour to ensure that if ruptured it will not escape the robot. The terms 'pressure vessel, bottle, and source tank' are used interchangeably. 
 
 
Hydraulics
 
- Robot can use non-inflammable liquid to actuate hydraulic devices e.g. cylinders.
 
- All hydraulic components on-board a robot must be securely mounted. Special care must be taken while mounting pump, accumulator and armour to ensure that if ruptured direct fluid streams will not escape the robot.
 
- All hydraulic liquids are required to be non corrosive and your device should be leak proof. Maximum allowed pressure is 8 bars.
 
- Participant must be able to indicate the used pressure with integrated or temporarily fitted pressure gauge.
 
- Entire hydraulic setup should be onboard, no external input (from outside the arena) could be given to the robot for functioning of its hydraulic system.
 

Weapons Systems
 
- Robots can have any kind of magnetic weapons, cutters, flippers, saws, lifting devices, spinning hammers etc. as weapons with following exceptions and limitations:
 
       - Liquid projectiles.
 
       - Any kind of inflammable liquid.
 
       - Flame-based weapons.
 
       - Any kind of explosive or intentionally ignited solid or potentially ignitable solid.
 
       - Nets, tape, glue, or any other entanglement device.
 
       - High power magnets or electromagnets.
 
       - Radio jamming, tazers, tesla coils, or any other high-voltage device.
 
       - Tethered or un-tethered projectiles.
 
       - Spinning weapons which do not come in contact with the arena at any point of time are allowed.         In no case should the arena be damaged by any bot.
 
- The competition will be played on a knock-out basis.There can be some hazards in the arena (subject to change, will be notified as soon as decided) 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: robowars@pragyan.org

Alpeksh Goyal          
Phone: +91 95243 80968

Atif Nabil                    
Phone: +91 72004 08167

Shwetang Shekhar
Phone: +91 90436 87308

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/160x200robowars.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Lanka Reloaded </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$10th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 40000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> A Unique Pick And Place Robotic Event </one>


			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:00</endtime>
 			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:00</endtime>
<starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 17:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/introduction/lanka.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Years ago the great hero Rama led an expedition to the mystical land of Sri Lanka, to rescue his wife Sita from the clutches of the daemon king Ravana. On their way they faced a great conundrum of crossing the vast Indian Ocean. Rama along with his army built a floating bridge across the ocean, the famous Ram Setu. We are all aware of the epic battle that took place between daemon king Ravana and Rama, resulting in Ravana’s defeat and salvage of Sita. We at Pragyan’13 give you an opportunity in rebuilding Ram Setu.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Please refer to Figure 1 at the bottom of the page.
 
- Each team has to make a manual robot capable of picking and placing tennis balls.
 
- A team may consist of maximum four members.
 
- The arena is divided in to 3 regions layer 0, layer 1 and layer 2.
 
- The robot will start from layer 0 where it will be put on a red square 40x40 cm2.
 
- The boulder region on layer 0 will have 12 balls. The robot can pick as many balls as it can.
 
- The robot has to climb a slope of 10 degress to reach layer 1.
 
- Layer 1 will be an 80x80 platform.
 
- Layer 1 and layer 2 will have a void bridge connecting them approximately 21 cm long.
 
- The bridge will have 12 sockets on them for the boulders.
 
- The robot has to drop the balls in to each of the slots.
 
- The bridge will be completed only if all the 12 balls have been dropped in to the slots.
 
- After the bridge is made the robot has cross it and get the final ball (resembling sita) and bring it back to layer 0. Where it has to be put on top of the pedestal to complete the event.
 
- The arena for the final round will be slightly modified
 
 
Arena

- Please refer to Figure 2 at the bottom of the page.
 
Dimensions
 
- Please refer to Figure 3 and Figure 4 at the bottom of the page.
 
After dropping the balls:

- Please refer to Figure 5 and Figure 6 at the bottom of the page.
 
Red Ball
 
- Please refer to Figure 6 at the bottom of the page. 
 
  
Scoring:
 
- +20 for successfully placing each ball into the slot.
 
- +10 For each additional ball picked up. If robot picks up two or more balls simultaneously from the boulder region
 
- -5 if the ball is dropped during transit, on or after the 100 slope
 
- -5 if the ball misses the slot and falls outside the arena
 
- +30 for crossing the bridge.
 
- +40 for getting the final ball and putting it on the pedestal at level zero.
 
- Final score = total score + time left in seconds.
 
  
Game rules:
 
- Each team can have maximum 3 trials.
 
- Each round will be of 15 min.
 
- The team will lose a trial if the bot malfunctions during that trial.
 
- The team is not allowed to touch the bot or arena during a trial, doing so will lead to termination of the trial.
 
- If the ball misses the bridge slot and falls outside, the ball will be put back to the boulder region.
 
- The bot can only cross the bridge after putting all the 12 balls into the slot.
 
- The best of the three trials will be considered for the final scoring.
 
- No points will be deducted, if the bot drops the ball, after picking it up completely or partially, in the boulder region. However, if the bot drops the balls on or after the slope, then negative points will be awarded, and the ball will be placed back in the boulder region.

</content>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/event_format/arenaFinal.jpg</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/event_format/arena1.png</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/event_format/lanka_dimensions.png</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/event_format/lanka_dimensions2.png</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/event_format/lanka_dimensions_aft.png</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/event_format/lanka_dimensions_aft2.png</pgimg>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/robovigyan/lanka_reloaded/event_format/lanka_redball.png</pgimg>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Lanka Reloaded.
 
 
 
General Rules
 
- Bot must fit into a square of 40cm x 40cm initially.
 
- The potential should not exceed 12V at any two points in the remote or the robot.
 
- The bot can have wired or wireless remote controlling system. In case of wired remote the wires should be bundled and should remain slack throughout the event.
 
- Teams found taking advantage of the tension in the wire shall be immediately disqualified.
 
- Only one person is allowed to control the bot.
 
- Members are not allowed to step over/touch the arena.
 
- Damaging of the arena in any way will lead to the disqualification of team.
 
- Decision of the judges will be final.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Frequesntly Asked Questions</pagename>
              <content>
Q1. Is it ok if more than 1 team participates from the same college?
 
Yes, it is completely fine for any number of teams to participate from the same college. However, in case judges feel that any two teams have copied the bot design from each other, both teams will be disqualified. 
 
Q2. Can more than four people participate per team?
 
Any number of people can be involved in making the bot. However, participation certificates, when awarded, will be given only to four members per bot. 
 
Q3. Is bonafide certificate from college necessary for the competition?
 
No. A valid photo identity proof, the student identity card, is sufficient. No bonafide is required
 
Q4. What power source can be used?
 
Any power source, is fine. However, potential difference between any two points, cannot exceed 12V DC, at any time during the run. 
 
Q5. What is the weight of the bot that is allowed?
 
There is no limitation on the weight of the bot, as long as it doesn't damage the arena
 
Q6. Are readymade dev-boards allowed?
 
Ready made dev boards, are accepted(Incl. Arduino).
 
Q7. Are ready-made grippers allowed?
 
The mechanism as such, must not be ready-made. Only the 'gripper', can be ready made. Gears etc can be purchased. But the assemblage as such must not be ready made. It is upto judges discretion to decide, if the mechanism is something you have actually put your effort into, or is it just an assembly job.
 
Contact the mentioned numbers, for any further queries. You can also email the queries to the email address given.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: lankareloaded@pragyan.org


Brahm Prakash Mishra
Phone: +91 94442 85995

Sethu Chidambaram
Phone: +91 95850 69119

Govinda Pandey
Phone: +91 96779 06037

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x410lanka.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/robovigyan.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname> Brainwork </itemname>
        <one> Food For Thought</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Pragyan Main Quiz </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 15000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> This Is THE Quiz </one>
			
<starttime>02-03-2013 16:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 19:00</endtime>

<starttime>02-03-2013 22:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 23:00</endtime>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/brainwork/pragyan_main_quiz/introduction/pragyanmainquiz.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Bring your grey cells to the party as Pragyan is back again with its flagship quiz. Far from classroom rote, this quiz is all about the world of Science and Technology.  Get ready for a roller coaster ride into the intense world of techno quizzing.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Prelims + Finals.

- No registration required.

- 6/8 teams in the finals.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Teams of 3 (max).
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Pragyan Main Quiz.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: pragyanmainquiz@pragyan.org


Ravikiran Ramaswamy 
Phone: +91 98842 96038

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/310x200mainquiz.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Sudoku Championship</itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 6000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Sudoku Solving Contest </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 11:30</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 12:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/brainwork/sudoku/introduction/sudoku.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Do you feel that the logical spirit inside does give you sleepless nights?

Do you dream of placing numbers in combinatorial grids while getting lost and running from chasing numbers who wants their place?

This Pragyan we bring you the Holy Mother of Puzzles. The number crunching puzzle popularised by Nikoli, meaning a single number, which saw its rapid rise to front page featuring in international newspapers, followed by being organized by World Puzzle Organisation. We take you to the World of Sudoku.

Whether you want to sing a tribute, like Peter Levy’s, or you love to solve it, you are heartily invited to the Dais. Let the spirit of curiosity ride you in solving the biggest mysteries of Sudoku’s number placements algorithms. Let the puzzler inside you come out and may the best puzzler set the stage on countdown-fire and win the title of the ‘Sudoku Champion’13’!

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Event Stages
 
- Sudoku Championship is an on-spot event.
 
Preliminary round
 
- The preliminary round consists of a set of puzzles for all the participants to solve in the limited time constraint. The best 25 move to next round. 
 
Final round
 
- Final round consists of 4 rounds which rigorously test the puzzle solving capabilities of a finalist. The puzzles are designed for testing both Left brain and Right brain and the Lateral thinking capabilities of the finalists. The details will be disclosed during the Finals.
 
- Candidates are expected to be prepared with the solving spirit of various variants to unleash the inner champion.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
Judging and Protest
 
- In parts where order or time plays an important role, the participant who solved need to raise their hands and a coordinator will come to their table and note the exact time of submission on their puzzle sheet.
 
- The winners of each round will be informed by message.
 
 
 
Ranking
 
- Individual ranking will be done by the method of summing. The results from different individual parts are summed up to get the final tally.
 
- Top 25 competitors will compete in the Final individual playoffs.
 
 
 
Code of Conduct
 
- All competitors are kindly asked to be in their tables before the official starting time of each round.
 
- The use of electronic device – including mobile phones, laptops, tablets, calculators, music players with headphones, iPods, kindle etc. will not be allowed.
 
 
 
Scoring
 
- In all puzzles in the championship, points are awarded only if the puzzle is completely correctly solved. Partial points will be explained further in the booklet.
 
- Solving time for the ‘Preliminary round’ is 60 minutes.
 
- Final round is a collection of rounds, and the total time is 120 minutes.
 
 
 
Eligibility
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Sudoku Championship.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: sudoku@pragyan.org


Anil Tilanthe
Phone: +91 97901 12459

Prateek Agarwal
Phone: +91 90439 40485

Rizwan Moiduni
Phone: +91 81488 18436

Rohini Muthuvelan
Phone: +91 97888 55625

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x140sudoku.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Biz Quiz</itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 13500$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Your Quintessential Business Quiz </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 18:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 23:00</endtime>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/brainwork/biz_quiz/introduction/bizquiz.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Are you the kind that thrives on the business section of the news every day?

We make you an offer you can’t refuse.

Pragyan is back with a bigger and better edition of the Pragyan Biz Quiz. From Apple to Zynga, do you have the wits to be crowned the champion of biz quizzing?

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Prelims + Finals.

- No registration required.

- 6/8 teams in the finals.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Teams of 3 (max).
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Biz Quiz.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: bizquiz@pragyan.org

Ashwin CV 
Phone: +91 94449 46198 

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x160bizquiz.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Event X </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 7000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> The Mystery Quiz </one>
			<starttime>03-03-2013 17:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 20:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/brainwork/eventx/introduction/quizx.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
The mystery quizzing event of Pragyan, Event X is the place to be for all you techno geeks.
We’ve seen the likes of Internet pop culture quiz and Gaming quiz in the previous editions. This next one might just be your forte. Gear up for the ride.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Prelims only.

- No registration required.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Teams of 3 (max).
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Event X.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: eventx@pragyan.org

Ashwin CV 
Phone: +91 94449 46198

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/240x200mysteryquiz.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Labyrinth</itemname>
            <main>Prize money worth   $$!!$$INR 30000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> The Online Treasure Hunt </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 08:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 23:00</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/brainwork/labyrinth/introduction/ideasBulb.png</pgimg>
              <content>
Labyrinth brings to you a series of puzzles, an enthralling treasure hunt of sorts. It is a quest that tests your code-cracking, brainstorming and lateral thinking, while subtly nudging your innate capacity to think outside the box. This Pragyan, experience thrills at par with being in an Indiana Jones adventure. Prepare yourself for twists and turns; tune your eyes and mind to spot the black cat in the dark room.
 
Labyrinth is a furious race that pushes its participants to the extreme of their abilities, urging them to delve deeper and unravel each layer of mystery as quickly as possible.  The race ends during Pragyan, when the most compelling levels of the event seek out only the worthy. This hunt promises to be an adrenaline packed race with contenders fighting to reach the end of the rainbow before the rest and claim the pot of gold that is rightfully theirs.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Play</pagename>
              <content>
- To play Labyrinth, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/brainwork/labyrinth/.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- This single stage multi-level event (40 - 50 levels) will serve as a run up to Pragyan, climaxing on the days of Pragyan 2013.
 
- This event will contain stages of varying difficulty levels, some more, some less challenging, with a beginner friendly learning curve.
 
- For all those who start it now; this will not be one of those riddles where you click through in some minutes. It will take you some levels to get a feeling of it, and you should be addicted when you get there.
 
- If you just are stuck, you might get some hints after trying for hours. Nothing wrong about them, they hardly take anything away from the satisfaction you get from solving a riddle; also you can be sure to learn a lot from all those riddles, if you solve them properly.
 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Every level has an answer or a method that would take you to the next level. Try all to get to the next  level; don't be limited to the picture or to the browser.
 
- The answer of a particular level gives you access to the next level.
 
- All answers are lower-case letters and numbers 0-9. Spaces, special characters are not allowed.
 
- Write down all usernames and passwords, and don't forget to bookmark your last level.
 
- Make up your mind about source codes. You may find something useful in the master plan of the page.
 
- Most important, don't limit yourself to the mouse. You have a keyboard, you have other programs on your computer, you have internet (to search and download stuff).
 
- Please try not to refresh the page. Refreshing pages where you submitted wrong answers would increase our record of your number of attempts.
 
- If you leave labyrinth midway, and come back to it later, you will be taken to the level where you left off.
 
- However, the amount of time you took for the game is calculated from the time you started playing, and is not the time you spent on the web site.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Mail to: labyrinth@pragyan.org

Aditya Muraletharan
Phone: +91 97893 89606

Siddharth Sekhar
Phone: +91 98406 04580

Navin Sridharan
Phone: +91 96001 22217

Vignesh Sushrutha
Phone: +91 94446 11242

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/410x150labyrinth.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>How Stuff Works </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 13500$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Uncommon Trivia About Everything Common </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 11:00</endtime>


<starttime>01-03-2013 16:30</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 19:30</endtime>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/brainwork/how_stuff_works/introduction/howstuffworks.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
A test of techno know- how and the workings of the world around us, Pragyan HSW gives you a chance to flaunt your geekiness on a whole new level. Expect to be challenged. We are waiting.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Prelims + Finals.
 
- No registration required.
 
- 6/8 teams in the finals.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Teams of 3 (max).
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in How Stuff Works.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: howstuffworks@pragyan.org

Suhas Srinivasan
Phone: +91 97912 15750

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/220x200howstuffworks.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/brainworks.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname> CodeIt </itemname>
        <one> Coders Do It Byte By Byte</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Bytecode </itemname>
            <main>Prize money worth   $$!!$$INR 87500$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Online programming contest </one>
			<starttime>03-03-2013 20:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 23:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/Codeit/bytecode/introduction/bytecode.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Picture this. The best brains in the world competing against you, coding against time to compile their most efficient programs. For those looking for a worldwide exposure of your coding skills, BYTECODE ‘13 sets the stage for you. Fight it out against competitors from different countries, and try to wrest the mantle of Top Coder.
 
Byte code or bite dust.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- This is an online event. Participation is possible from anywhere in the world.
 
- Bytecode is a 5 hour ACM ICPC style algorithm intensive online programming competition.
 
- We put up problem statements that define what the input to your program is and what it must output.
 
- You write programs that do the necessary processing / transformation from input to output.
 
- You submit the programs to our online judge (which is an automated checker).
 
- The Judge instantly checks if your program works fine, by testing it with several inputs.
 
- The Judge gives you a response.
 
- The objective is to solve problems and score maximal total points.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- A team may consist of a maximum of 3 members (not necessarily from the same institute).
 
- The final ranking is based on the total number of problems solved, ties broken by the total time consumed.
 
- The total time is the sum of the time consumed for each solved problem.
 
- The time consumed for a solved problem is the time elapsed from the beginning of the contest to the submission of the first accepted run for that problem (in minutes) plus 20 minutes for every other run for that problem before the accepted one. For an unsolved problem no time consumed is computed.
 
- There is no partial credit for any problem.
 
- After running a program against our test data, the judge produces a status message. This is also output to the user.
 
- List of languages allowed: C, C++, C#, Java, PHP, Perl, Ruby, Python, Haskell, Clojure and Scala.
 
- No system calls are allowed other than input output routines.
 
- In case of any discrepancies, the organizers' decision will be final.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: bytecode@pragyan.org

Abhishek Parthasarathy
Phone: +91 97910 63602

Aditya Muraletharan
Phone: +91 97893 89606

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x210bytecode.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Digital Fortress</itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$26th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 30000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Live Online Hacking Contest </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 08:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 23:00</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/Codeit/digital_fortress/introduction/logo.png</pgimg>
              <content>
Welcome to Digital Fortress – the coders’ battlefield to infiltrate the enemy and capture the flag.  Are you the next hacker waiting to take the world by storm?  Breach this fortress. 
The event is held online going live during Pragyan.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Participants are required to register for the event in pairs of two advance -- optional.
 
- Two rounds have been planned.
 
- One comprising of level based online hacking round.
 
- The final round being “Control the Grid” round.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Round 1</pagename>
              <content>
- It is a level-based contest.

- All teams will start at Lvl. 1 through Lvl. 9001.

- Each level will consist of a challenge that will require the contestant to obtain a secret flag.

- At the end of the alloted time, the participants from the top two levels will progress to round two.

- The structure of each level as follows:-

	- You will be presented with an attack scenario on a page.

	- The types of levels will be:-

		- Cryptography

		- Reverse Engineering
		
		- Web Vulnerabilities
		
		- Common Sense!

	- Once you have exploited a vulnerability, you will find a key that we try to keep in plain sight.

	- Entering the key at the DF portal will reveal the next round.
	
	- The levels must be completed in strict sequence.

	- Don't share keys; it is a stupid thing to do.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: digitalfortress@pragyan.org

Deepak M 
Phone: +91 99412 53189

Vignesh Paneerselvam P
Phone: +91 94873 66850

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/260x210digi.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Treasure Hunt </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$26th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 16000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> An Adventure In Linux </one>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/Codeit/treasure_hunt/introduction/treasure-hunt.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
The stage is set.
The maze is virtual.
You have the most dangerous weapon
– “The TERMINAL.”
An event for the adventurous and the curious.
Explore the surroundings, hack into the network, break the clues and voila you are there.
A challenge for you to prove your linux skill!
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- The preliminary Round will be an ONLINE QUIZ.
 
- The quiz will have both objective and subjective questions.
 
- Around 20 teams will move on to the FINALS
 
- The teams will be provided with an username and password to log into a server set up for the event.
 
- When logged in, each team will get a terminal to use.
 
- The maze will consist of around 20 - 30 places, With a clue to the next place in each checkpoint.
 
- The number of commands availabe to the users will be limited. The command set will be mailed to the teams, prior to the event.
 
- The clues will be questions related to FOSS, Linux, and of course Networking.
 
- A maximum of 3 life-lines will be provided incase the team is unable to move on using the given clue.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Use of a Life-line, leads to deduction of points (3 lifelines at each check point).
 
- 3 people per team.
 
- Use of restricted commands, invokes a warning. If a team uses one of the restricted commands a second time, they will be disqualified.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: treasurehunt@pragyan.org

Harish 
Phone: +91 77086 62314 

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x150treasurehunt.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Crack The Shell </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$26th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 25000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Online Shell Scripting Event </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 08:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 23:00</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/Codeit/crack_the_shell/introduction/crack-the-shell.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Are you a FOSS enthusiast?
Do you love the terminal?
This event is just for you!
 
We're guessing that you're familiar with the shell.  For those without a clue, let's simply say Shell is where all those Linux Commands are typed out. The Shell is powerful. Powerful enough to do anything. But then, how should `anything` be defined?

'Crack the Shell' is all about solving simple day to day tasks on your computer through the terminal.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- The first round is selective. All other rounds are eliminative. The top teams in each round qualify to the next.
 
- Round 1: Online quiz
 
       - 24th February, 04:00 pm to 25th February, 11:59am.
 
- Further details will be put up soon!

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- A team can consist of a maximum of 2 members.
 
- A team can consist of participants from different Institutions.
 
- Participants will be briefed on how to proceed in a round before the round begins.
 
- No participant can be in more than one team. Being so leads to disqualification of both the teams.
 
- Decision of the judges will be binding.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: cracktheshell@pragyan.org

Harish 
Phone: +91 77086 62314 

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/crack.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Adaventure </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$21st February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 30000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Test Your 1v1 Coding Skills </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 08:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 23:00</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/Codeit/adaventure/introduction/adaventure.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Today, reality cannot be fathomed without the help of the virtual world. And in the helm of the virtual world rule the computer geeks. And for them as is for everyone, awaits a crazy challenge. Inheriting its name from Lady Ada, who is considered the first computer programmer of the world, Adaventure epitomizes fun and coding in the software arena. Versatile? You bet. A huge crowd puller and an outstanding success rate imply that it’s not all easy. Hundreds of talented students are on the race. The game is on! Do get some rest before you need it.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Crazy Programming </pagename>
              <content>
Introduction 
 
Crazy Programming is all about how efficient one can code in C. The code which carries the least weight (calculated as given below) wins. This encourages the participants to write crazy codes, hence the name of the event! The participants are given a set of problems for which they’ll have to code in C with as less of the programming language constructs as possible.
 
 
 
Rules and Regulations
 
- The C code that the user submits should compile with gcc-4.4.6+ (Turbo C shouldn’t be used).
 
- The prize structure will be put up on the website and any disputes regarding the prize money should be addressed to the Pragyan Treasurer.
 
- The live leader board is only for Information purpose and can’t be cited as the final reference.
 
- The decision of the Adaventure team shall be final and binding.
 
- The objective of the event is to test a programmer’s ability to write correct code and also to minimize the Code Weight. This is meant to be fun event and not an algorithmic challenge.
 
- To view the criterion used to compute the weight of the user submitted program, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/CodeIt/adaventure/.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Bot Wars</pagename>
              <content>
Introduction
 
- Code an AI for the scenario.
 
- Your AI will be pitted against other AIs in a tournament.
 
- Anticipate, predict and expect the other AI's move. It is this ability of yours that can make you win. Thinking through the options and working through scenarios in your mind will give you the competitive edge and potential winning move.

  
Scenario
 
- Each team will have a total of 6 units:      
       - 3 foot soldiers
       - 2 tanks
       - 1 chopper 
       - 1 structure : Headquarter
 
- Note:
       - Each unit will be able to move a specific number of grids in each turn.
 
       - Maximum being the chopper and minimum by the foot soldiers.
 
       - Damages that they can dish out and their range also vary.
 
 
Objective
 
- Destroy the opponent's HQ before they destroy yours.
 
Or
 
- Eliminate all of their units.
 
- Turn based: You can move one of your units once, and then wait for the opponent's turn before making a move again.
 
 
Arena:
 
- 20 X 15 grid map.
 
 
Format
 
- The AIs will go through a tournament.
 
- In the league round each AI will be played against every other AIs.
 
- For the next round 12 AIs will be selected, out of which 6 will move to the next round.
 
- Out of the 6 AIs, 2 will remain for the Final Round. 

- The final match will be shown live.
  
 
Rules and Regulations
 
- Participants will have to download the API for creating the AI and submit the AI file through email. 
 
- We will be providing a demo AI for testing purpose.
 
- Prizes are based on tournament outcome only.
 
- The live leader board is only for Information purpose and can’t be cited as the final reference.
 
- The decision of the Adaventure team shall be final and binding.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: adaventure@pragyan.org

S Swapna 
Phone: +91 98406 76704

Ram Dayal Vaishnav 
Phone: +91 81448 38618

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x150adaventure.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/codeit.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname> Pragyan's Got Talent</itemname>
        <one> Come, Show, Conquer</one>
        <page>
          <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
          <pgimg>/13/home/events/pragyan_got_talent/Introduction/pgt.jpg</pgimg>
          <content>
A great talent yearns for an opportunity to rise to the challenge. Infotainment at Pragyan'13 presents an amazing platform to flaunt these creative talents imbibed within each one of us, offering an impressive show to participants and observers alike. A chance, to unleash your artistic talents with a performance that will keep the audience enthralled and leave the judges breathless.
Amidst this immense competition and prizes worth 40K INR, do you think you’ve got what it takes to rule the stage? Find out, this Pragyan at NIT-Trichy. May the best performers win!

</content>
        </page>
        <page>
          <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
          <content>
- To register, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/events/pragyan_got_talent/.
 
- Any creative art Eg. Magic, Juggling, Acrobtics, Shadowgraphy, Sand Animation, freestyle football, Light Painting, Water Art, puppetry, mimicry, Music, Beat Boxing, Stunts and Dance, etc. can be performed.
               (Or) A social message Eg. 'No Smoking’ can be conveyed by innovative means Eg. through dance, plays, short movies, picture story, animation etc.
 
- The registered teams must require the performance video or the Youtube link on the pragyan.nitt facebook page before February 20th,2013.
 
- 20% points will be awarded to number of likes for the video on the Pragyan.nitt facebook page and 80% points will be allotted for the performance during Pragyan.
 
- Special technical requirements (if any) should be communicated before 20th February.
 
- Shortlisting will be done based on the videos and results will be announced before 11th February.

</content>
        </page>
        <page>
          <pagename>Event Format </pagename>
          <content>
- Teams which are short-listed will perform on Pragyan stage during Pragyan’13 (2nd March, 2013).
 
- The duration of this performance can be upto 10 minutes maximum.
 
- 20% points will be allotted for the video likes on the Pragyan.nitt facebook page (https://www.facebook.com/pragyan.nitt) and 80% points will be awarded for the performance during Pragyan.
 
- Performance points will be awarded solely for creativity and crowd appeal!
 
- The participants will be allowed to have a rehearsal on the Pragyan stage on the day before the performance.

</content>
        </page>
        <page>
          <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
          <content>

Saqib: +91 98845 68588 

Priyesh: +91 98400 45954 

Or mail to Infotainment at infotainment@pragyan.org

</content>
        </page>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/PGT.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Manigma</itemname>
        <one>Fine Line Between The Leader and The Laggard</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Dalal Street </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 40000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> The Virtual Stock Exchange </one>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/manigma/dalal_street/Introduction/dalal.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Dalal Street is a virtual stock trading game. As opposed to conventional stock picking games, Dalal Street actually allows the players to trade among themselves. Trading is facilitated by an electronic exchange running from our servers. The player accumulating maximum wealth by trading will be crowned the winner.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Each participant is provided with a fixed amount of virtual money initially for trading.
 
- At the start of the game, shares of few Indian companies will be offered for sale at previous day's BSE closing price. More shares may come into market later to encourage new participants and to add liquidity to the market. 
 
- Participants can do market research of these companies before choosing which stocks to buy. Stocks will be offered on a first come first served basis. Trading will be allowed in these shares starting from day one.
 
- Players should watch the markets carefully to decide their strategy. Apart from watching the direction of prices in our virtual exchange. they should keep in touch with real world happenings too, to have the first mover advantage. A bundle containing various RSS feeds providing the latest market data, will be provided to the users. They can use their favourite RSS reader to remain in touch with the market directions. Besides this, we will provide the current price of the stocks in BSE too. Users can use this as an indicator of the stock's health. 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Dalal Street is strictly only for college students and an individual event.
 
- Any market manipulation technique is to be avoided, and might result in disqualification of the participant.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: dalalstreet@pragyan.org

V Shriram
Phone: +91 94455 58781

Hari Venugopalan
Phone: +91 81440 64012

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/210x200dalal.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> The Ultimate Manager</itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 16000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Test Your Management Skills </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 15:30</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/manigma/the_ultimate_manager/Introduction/ulti-manager.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Enter the winding and twisting world of business- if you have the audacity to look into intricate details, if new ideas seem to amaze you, if you think you are a genius and ready to face challenges, if you enjoy finding the lost clues after assessing the intricate facts and analogies and through the relevant curves and graphs approach solutions, then come unlock the Sherlock in you at “The Ultimate Manager”.

Here is a chance to showcase your managerial prowess where a holistic testing of various aspects of management will be done. He who comes out unscathed is he who succeeds as making money requires not just hard work, but sometimes common sense. A slight anticipation and a little wit serve better. Unleash your imagination and talents at a platform where there is a lot to learn and earn.
 
The event will give the participants a feel of various situations a manager could face in the day to day business environment, consisting of stress and fun filled situations. 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Bell the Dozen- The Online Gateway!
 
- From 17th Feb to 28th Feb, everyday one question will be uploaded in the facebook page of The Ultimate Manager after 10 pm. The individual answering correctly the maximum no. of times within this period will be eligible to play directly the second round i.e. Teamspiel. The first correct answer will be taken as the winner.

- Facebook page - www.facebook.com/pages/The-Ultimate-Manager/259468800787479.
 
  
First Round: Cuestionario
 
- 20 multiple choice questions that check the general awareness of the participants with regards to management (to get an idea about the participants’ inclination towards management)
 
- 40 participants will be shortlisted and grouped into teams of 2 (so as to assess their ability to perform as a team given a hostile situation, thereby bringing out the best in them).
 
  
Second Round: Teamspiel
 
- Switch 
 
       - A picture will be given and participants will have to construct a Story based on it.
 
       - A game that appraises: 
 
               - How well they convey their ideas and the fluency in the speech (verbal communication skills).
 
               - How well they connect with each other’s ideas and carry it forward.
 
               - How well they are able to attract and entertain the audience.
 
- Blame Game
 
       - Each participant will critically analyze their partner based on the performance in Switch.
  
 
Third Round: Krigszon- The Final Destination
 
- Part 1: The participants will be given an HR caselet and they will be required to provide an analysis based on it.
 
- Part 2: An object will be given and the participants will have to prepare a marketing strategy and promotion for it. 

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- It’s an individual event. Any number of entries from a college are allowed.
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in The Ultimate Manager.
 
- The first round is an objective round.
 
- The second and third rounds are situation based.
 
- For team rounds, teams will be formed at the discretion of the judges on the venue, so participants need not come with a team.
 
- Judge’s decision will be final and binding.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: ultimatemanager@pragyan.org

Anshuman Dutta
Phone: +91 95006 69607

Fatima Amanulla Khan
Phone: +91 82209 31764

Shashank
Phone: +91 97914 04561

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/210x260ultimanager.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Pragyan Premier League </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$15th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 15000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Virtual Cricket Management Game </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 13:00</endtime>
 <starttime>02-03-2013 18:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 20:00</endtime>


            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/manigma/pragyan_premier_league/Introduction/ppl1.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Pragyan Premier League is a Cricket Management Event, in which participants have to participate in an auction of players, and decide their playing strategy in a virtual Cricket tournament.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- Round 1 of Pragyan Premier League is an online round that takes place before Pragyan. A portal is opened online for a few days, where participants have to select and finalize their squad of players.
 
- Once the window for buying players closes, the participant is made to select his team for the upcoming match, send players for training, manage his finances etc. The performance of the participant's team is determined by a Virtual Cricket league running in the backend, the training received by the players, their fatigue level etc.
 
- This virtual league runs for a week or so, after which, the top 16 teams from Round 1 move on to Round 2.
 
- Round 2 happens on campus, in NIT Trichy. A live auction is conducted, where participants are made to buy players for the upcoming cricket matches.
 
- In round 2, participants are made to go head-to-head in a knockout round.
 
- The finalists of Round 2 and the winner of the third-place match, are declared the winners of Pragyan Premier League.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Pragyan Premier League is open for all, and is a team event, having two managers per team.
 
- The result declared by the Event Managers will be considered final.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: premierleague@pragyan.org

Hari Venugopalan 
Phone: +91 81440 64012

V Shriram
Phone: +91 94455 58781

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/150x470PPL.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/manigma.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Chill Pill</itemname>
        <one>Beating The Blues</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Pragyan Cube Open </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 70000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Rubik's Cube Solving Contest </one>
			
<starttime>02-03-2013 12:30</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 19:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 08:30</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 15:00</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/chill_pill/pragyan_cube_open/Introduction/cube-open.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Here’s the challenge for your nimble fingers! Flaunt your mastery of the world’s best 3D-puzzle, the cube!
A WCA registered event and open to cubers of all ages, Pragyan 2013 brings to you Pragyan Cube Open.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
The following cube events will be conducted:
 
- 2x2x2
 
- 3x3x3
 
- 4x4x4
 
- 5x5x5
 
- Pyraminx
 
- Square – 1
 
- 3x3x3 One Hand
 
- 3x3x3 Blind Fold
 
- 3x3x3 Fewest Moves
 
- 3X3X3 Multiple Blind Folds
 
- Megaminx

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Events will be conducted as per WCA rules.
 
- Participants must bring their own cubes.
 
- Competitions may have time limits per round of an event.
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Pragyan Cube Open.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: cubeopen@pragyan.org

Mathan
Phone: +91 95664 24783

Clifford
Phone: +91 88706 67923

Jaya Ram
Phone: +91 90429 29871

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x310cubeopen.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Crime Busters </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 15000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> The Pragyan Murder Mystery </one>
			<starttime>02-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 12:00</endtime>
 
<starttime>02-03-2013 16:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 19:00</endtime>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/chill_pill/crime_busters/Introduction/crime-busters.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
The radical distinction of Crime Busters from other events is that it is purely non technical. It is for the fast paced minds but purely logical and brainy, sure to say brilliant. An event where NITTians as well as our honored guests can come to blow off steam, away from all the robotics and brain cracking coding. With immense lateral thinking involved, Crime Busters is uncomplicated but not to be reckoned easy.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- On-Spot Event
 
- The preliminary round consists of logical questions, brain teasers and GK questions. From this, a maximum of 7 teams will be shortlisted for the finals.
 
- The final round comprises of two stages.
 
- In the first stage, team's basic knowledge in solving questions based on picture analysis, situational cases etc. will be tested.
 
- Finally, a mystery case file will be given and teams should solve it in the given time frame.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- A team can consist of a maximum of 3 participants.
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Crime Busters.
 
- Final winners will be those who solve the case with perfection, deciphering the maximum number of clues and thus providing the complete evidence pointing to the culprit.
 
- If the team can find the motive of crime, bonus points will be given.
 
- In case of a tie, points in other stages of events may be considered. If participants seek extra clues other than which is given in the case file, then points will be deducted for them.
 
- Malpractice during any stage of the event will lead to disqualification of the whole team.
 
- At any stage, the decision of judges will be final.
 
- Any rules are viable to change and will be announced before the commencement of the event.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: crimebusters@pragyan.org

Gokul Suresh
Phone: +91 98432 60931

Jose Tom M
Phone: +91 78451 05954

Rakesh R Nair
Phone: +91 72001 20985

R Ajay Kumar
Phone: +91 96772 13375

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x140crime.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname> Zombie Escapades </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$25th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 18000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> The Technical Scavenger Hunt </one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 12:00</endtime>


<starttime>01-03-2013 12:30</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 18:00</endtime>


<starttime>01-03-2013 18:30</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 20:00</endtime>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/chill_pill/zombie_escapades/Introduction/zombie-escapades.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Amid intriguing challenges for our brain, here’s an event to challenge your brawn too! Zombie Escapades is the treasure hunt of Pragyan, which evaluates your reasoning skills and judges your ability to put scientific principles into action. You need to decipher the codes and clues and find your way to the treasure!

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- On-Spot Event.
 
- Prelims will consist of a few puzzles(Scientific application, logic, math, word, apti) and will be for 1 hour.
 
- All teams that register will be allowed to participate in the prelims. However, only 15 teams will be shortlisted to participate in Zombie Escapades.
 
- In the next round, each of the 15 teams must complete 6 different tasks at 6 different locations in a sort of treasure hunt. This will take a maximum of 3 hours.
 
- The 6 teams that take the least overall time to complete all the tasks will move to the next round. The rest are eliminated.
 
- Finals consists of 1 task, where the 6 teams are each provided a variety of raw materials to choose from to build a working model of some kind within 1 hour.
 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- Each team consists of no less than two and no more than three members.
 
- All students with a valid identity card from their respective educational institution are eligible to participate in Zombie Escapades.
 
- Participants are not allowed to get calculators.
 
- They should not use any means of copying or cheating. Indulging in such activities will lead to disqualification.
 
- During the treasure hunt they are supposed to hand over their cell phones to the coordinator and are allowed to use cycles.
 
- In the final round teams are not allowed to use anything apart from what is given to them.
 
- Other details will be provided at the beginning of the event.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: zombieescapades@pragyan.org

Diksha Gohlyan 
Phone: +91 74182 70719

Sneha Priya 
Phone: +91 72006 15083

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/200x160zombie.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Take One </itemname>
            <main>Registration Deadline: $$!!$$26th February, 2013$$%%$$$$##$$Prize money worth $$!!$$INR 26000$$%%$$</main>
            <one> Short Movie Making </one>
			<starttime>03-03-2013 13:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 16:30</endtime>

            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <pgimg>/13/home/events/chill_pill/take_one/Introduction/takeone.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Ever wanted to make something that captures everyone’s imagination, that which shocks or entertains, that which makes people laugh and that which makes them cry, that which motivates people or shatters them with brute reality or just distracts all from their problems and voice your opinions and ideas?
Do you fashion yourself to be the next Ratnam, Ray or Tarantino? Do you love to put on a different personality and live another life?
Pragyan 13 brings you Take One, the short film making contest.
The contestants are given an option to choose from any one or more of the given styles of movie making and are expected to come up with original, non-documentary entries made in any of the styles.
The main judging criteria are creativity in implementation, direction, editing, presentation etc. Also provide a short write up on your implementation of the topic as well as a short description of your video.  

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
- The Participants are required to produce their movie according to the rules and regulations stated.
 
- The Selected entries will be intimated through phone and website, and will be screened during pragyan in the presence of a judge.
 
- The Entries have to be mailed (the youtube links) to the below mentioned email id or directly sent by post in a dvd.
 
- The Final render should be in avi or mpeg4 format.
 
- Judge's decision is final.
 
- Plagiarized or heavily inspired content will not be entertained and will lead to disqualification.

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulations</pagename>
              <content>
- The entries have to be original. Plagiarized content will lead to disqualification.
 
- No restriction on genre
 
- The movie should have been made after 2012
 
- No restriction on the number of entries per college.
 
- Entries cannot exceed 15 minutes including the time for titles and credits.
 
- Maximum of 15 people can appear as part of the cast and 10 people behind the scenes.
 
- Entries can be in any regional language but English subtitles are mandatory.
 
- Presence of any form of vulgarity or obscenity will not be tolerated and will lead to direct disqualification.
 
- The number of entries screened at the event is solely decided by the organizers and subject to time availability.
 
- The short film has to be submitted in a CD or a DVD or youtube link has to be mailed.
 
- Presence of participants is not a must. The CD or DVD can be sent by postal mail.
 
- Entries that are of unrecognized video formats shall not be considered.
 
- Participants should encode the video in standard formats.(avi or mpeg)

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename>Contacts</pagename>
              <content>
Email: takeone@pragyan.org

Kandharaj
Phone: +91 88076 04965

Nishanth
Phone: +91 99941 30998 

</content>
            </page>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/410x150takeone.jpg</imgurl>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/chillpill.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
    </children>
  </item>
  <item>
    <itemname>Highlights</itemname>
    <children>
      <item>
        <itemname>Guest Lectures </itemname>
        <one> Lectures, a class apart! </one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Gerard Rego</itemname>
            <one>Gerard Rego
Director, Ecosystem and Developer Experience, Nokia India</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Gerard-Rego.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Gerard Rego </pagename>
              <content>
Gerard Rego has made himself known as an entrepreneur and investor in the tech industry, through an extensive career that spans more than two decades. Note that "tech industry" here is used in a very panoramic sense. Mr Rego's experience reaches across supply chain management, manufacturing, renewables, IT, internet, CAE and Aerospace and Defense industries. He is a fellow of Wharton Business School and is known especially for his work in business modeling and product innovation. He is currently director of Ecosystem and Developer Experience(EDX), Nokia India, which makes him largely responsible for Nokia's app development platform and the Windows Phone Marketplace. He is also cofounder of Vayugrid, a biodiesel company.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Thanu Padmanabhan</itemname>
            <one>Thanu Padmanabhan
Theoretical Physics and Cosmology</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Thanu-Padmanabhan.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Thanu Padmanabhan </pagename>
              <content>
Thanu Padmanabhan is an Indian theoretical physicist who has distinguished himself with fundamental contributions to several areas of astrophysics.He received his Ph.D. from the Tata Institute of Fundamental Research, and went on to do his postdoctoral research at University of Cambridge, UK. Currently, he is a distinguished Professor at the Inter-University Centre for Astronomy and Astrophysics, Pune. Books and research papers published by him have made a significant impact in his field. Dr. Padmanabhan has received numerous national and international awards for his work, including the Padma Shri in 2007.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Steven Furber</itemname>
            <one>Steven Furber
ARM and SpiNNaker</one>
<starttime>01-03-2013 11:30</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 13:30</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Steve-Furber.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Steve Furber </pagename>
              <content>
Steve Furber is the ICL Professor of Computer Science at the University of Manchester. He was one of the pioneering designers of the BBC Micro Computer System and the ubiquitous ARM microprocessor architecture in the 80's. One can understand the scale of its popularity today, with customer reports of 2011 suggesting that ARM microprocessors were used in 95% of smartphones and 90% of hard disk drives. More recently, his work has focused on biologically inspired computation. His latest project called SpiNNaker, is an attempt to build a new kind  of computer that directly mimics the workings of the human brain using a massive parallel processing system. The finished Spinnaker will model 1% of the human brain's capability, which is quite an achievement considering the capacity of the brain. His research interests also include asynchronous logic design and power-efficient computing.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Tessy Thomas</itemname>
            <one>Tessy Thomas
Project Director, Agni V</one>
<starttime>01-03-2013 09:30</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 11:30</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Tessy-Thomas.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Tessy Thomas </pagename>
              <content>
Tessy Thomas is the Project Director for Agni-V missile, which was successfully tested on 19 April 2012 by the DRDO. She is the first woman scientist to head a missile project in India. She has been lauded by Dr. Manmohan Singh an example of a "woman making her mark in a traditionally male bastion and decisively breaking the glass ceiling". She was conferred the Lal Bahadur Shastri National Award by the President in October 2012.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Rohan Dixit</itemname>
            <one>Rohan Dixit
Neuroimaging of Meditation, BrainBot</one>
<starttime>01-03-2013 15:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 17:00</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Rohan-Dixit.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rohan Dixit </pagename>
              <content>
Rohan Dixit is a cognitive neuroscience researcher, who founded the neurotechnology startup 'Brainbot'. Through his research at the Stanford Medical Center, he explored the “resting state” of the human mind using functional magnetic resonance imaging. Rohan later continued his research on the human brain by neuroimaging meditation at Harvard-MIT-MGH Martinos Center. Using the mind waves recorded, he created a dynamic, brain-aware application, which would help users to turn the internal process of mindfulness into objective measure.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>David Christian</itemname>
            <one>David Christian
Big History</one>
<starttime>02-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 16:00</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/David-Christian.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> David Christian </pagename>
              <content>
David Christian is one of the world's most renowned historians, widely known for creating an interdisciplinary approach known as Big History. It is an academic discipline which examines history scientifically from the Big Bang to the present. Originally an expert on Russia and the Soviet Union, Christian has been determined to try to teach history on the largest possible scale. He is now a professor at San Diego State University. He has authored many popular books including 'Maps of Time', which fetched him the World History Association Book Prize in 2005.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Anil Kakodkar</itemname>
            <one>Anil Kakodkar
Nuclear Man</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Anil-Kakodkar.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Anil Kakodkar </pagename>
              <content>
Anil Kakodkar is an eminent Indian nuclear scientist. He played a major role in India's Peaceful Nuclear Tests conducted in the 1970s, which helped India assert its sovereignty. Dr. Kakodkar has been instrumental in the development of several indigenous nuclear reactors. His exceptional leadership during his tenure as the chairperson of the Atomic Energy Commission of India led to a significant boost to India's nuclear power programme. In recognition of his work, he was awarded the Padma Vibushan in 2009.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Richard Noble</itemname>
            <one>Richard Noble
Fastest Man in the World</one>
<starttime>01-03-2013 21:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 23:00</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Richard-Noble.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Richard Noble </pagename>
              <content>
Coming up Soon!!!

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Chris Phillips</itemname>
            <one>Chris Phillips
The Invisible Man</one>
<starttime>02-03-2013 20:30</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 22:00</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/guest_lecture/newv13/Chris-Phillips.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Chris Phillips </pagename>
              <content>
Coming up Soon!!!

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/gl.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Pengufest</itemname>
        <main>Awesome Google goodies await every participant</main>
        <one>The FOSSinating penguin</one>
		<starttime>02-03-2013 10:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 12:30</endtime>


<starttime>02-03-2013 13:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 15:00</endtime>

<starttime>02-03-2013 15:30</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:30</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 13:00</endtime>

 <starttime>03-03-2013 15:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 18:30</endtime>

        <page>
          <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
          <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/pengufest/introduction/pengufest.jpg</pgimg>
          <content>	
"Soft power is like water, A single water drop is powerless, but numerous water drops are torrential. Open source is such a soft power".                                            --Taoism of Open Source; Chen Nan Yang

Ever felt that the best things in life come free? Does a bespoke virtual world amaze you and toying with it irresistible? Have no clue on what’s this all about? Come aboard, Free and Open Source Software or FOSS takes a new dimension, this year at Pragyan 13’.

Beckoning all self-proclaimed geeks (both wannabe and established) with even a passing interest in FOSS. We present to you Pengufest. Pengufest as its name suggests celebrates the Penguin and what it all stands for.

Ever pondered why Android dominates the international scenario by a large margin or how science has revolutionized the world? If the two seem irrelevant, think again. What is free, open and modifiable by all is what makes for a revolution.

And this is not far away. Coming Pragyan be sure to grab your favorite snack and immerse into the world of FOSS, Linux and GNOME. Want an expert opinion? Discussion with peers? Game for a competition? It all ends here and begins anew.

An opportunity to kick start the journey of novices, streamline the path for the established and a chance to divulge the knowledge for the experts. Like all things open source, it is community driven. Here, you are a part of the community.

For newbies or veterans Pengufest promises to be a ride not to be missed. Hop on and discover what you have missed. FOSS is a religion.
</content>
        </page>
        <page>
          <pagename> Speakers </pagename>
          <content>
For details on the speakers at Pengufest, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/pengufest/.

</content>
        </page>
        <page>
          <pagename> Schedule </pagename>
          <content>
The Schedule has not been finalized yet. A couple of talks may be added. The sessions are as follows:

  -  Mr. Hari Shankaran, Co Founder at Interviewstreet,

            Built interviewstreet.com and hackerrank on "Building a company from 0 to Million dollars"

  -  Mr. Krishnan Parthasarathi, Software Engineer Redhat! on "Gluster FS

            GlusterFS is a powerful network/cluster filesystem written in user space which uses FUSE (Filesystem in User Space) to hook itself with VFS layer.          GlusterFS takes a layered approach to the file system, where features are added/removed as per the requirement. Though GlusterFS is a File System, it uses already tried and tested disk file systems like ext3, ext4, xfs, etc. to store the data. It can easily scale up to petabytes of storage which is available to user under a single mount point.

  -  Mr. Muthu Subramanian,  Independent Consultant, Novell on Libre Office

          LibreOffice is the most powerful and viable Free Software office suite, available cross platform. This session would be a treat to would-be libreoffice hackers via a small hacking session. The proposed session would first give an introduction to libreoffice then take a simple task (mostly from the Calc module) and guide the audience through the task. This way the hackers would get a chance to hack libreoffice and also more importantly be able to contribute as individuals and teams.Virtualbox image containing opensuse 11.3 plus source+build of libreoffice would also be available.

</content>
        </page>
        <page>
          <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
          <content>
Email: pengufest@pragyan.org

Arvind M
+91 94458 13295

Jeh
+91 95669 39866

</content>
        </page>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/pengufest.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Exhibitions and Sangam</itemname>
        <one>Where vision gets built</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname> Exhibitions </itemname>
            <one>Exhibitions</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/exhibitions.jpg</imgurl>
            <children>
              <item>
                <itemname>Vintage Cars</itemname>
                <one>Experience the Royalty yourself!</one>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/exhibitions/newv13/vintage.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename> Vintage Vehicles </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/exhibitions/exhibitions/cars_2.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
A swanky car, carrying art works all over in flashing red, races past its counterpart and comes to a halt with a 90-degree swirl. A peep through the window takes you on a journey of woods. Or so it seems.

The upholsteries, dashboard, steering wheel, gearbox, floor mat and the roof, all reflect the sheen of wooden brown. A closer look will reveal the hand strokes involving laborious work of painting on the plastic fibre that is fixed over the interiors in different shades of brown.

It is not every day that you get to see a gleaming black car manufactured in 40's in all its glory honking past you on the streets. But when you're at Pragyan you can be sure to see such four wheel beauties! The collection starts from classic and vintage eras and drowns into luxury cars and bikes of each decade.

This edition, we are going to take you back to transportation’s early years of serving the masses. Prepare yourself  for a pleasant surprise and look out for cars and bikes that you must have never ridden in this century.

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname>CVRDE</itemname>
                <one>CVRDE</one>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/exhibitions/newv13/cvrde.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename> CVRDE </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/exhibitions/exhibitions/drdo_cover.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
DEFENCE RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ORGANISATION
   
Pragyan '13 brings you an exclusive sneak peek into the elite Indian arsenal, with an array of Exhibitions by Defence Research and Development Organization, India. Headquartered in New Delhi, DRDO has a network of 51 laboratories which are deeply engaged in developing technology related to aeronautics, armaments, electronics, combat vehicles, engineering systems, missiles, advanced computing and simulation, special materials, naval systems, information systems and agriculture. The organization is supported by more than 5,000 scientists and about 25,000 other scientific, technical and supporting personnel. Tasked with lengthening and strengthening India’s‘stick’, to be wielded for preserving peace, DRDO has made tremendous progress in the development of missiles, weapons, tanks, light combat aircraft, radars, electronic warfare systems etc.

 
CVRDE

This edition of Pragyan promises to offer a glance at the elite Indian arsenal as The Combat Vehicles Research and Development Establishment (CVRDE), Chennai a laboratory of DRDO sets its stall here. The CVRDE is responsible for equipping India’s frontline defences with superior quality combat vehicles since 1965.

Their area of work is to design, develop, manufacture prototypes and performance evaluation of Tracked Combat vehicles and Specialist tracked vehicles. These are mostly armoured vehicles like the likes of the Arjun Tank, Ajeya Tank, Armoured Scouting vehicles, Armoured Ambulances among many other products.

Pragyan 13 invites you to have the privilege of seeing CVRDE with their models and the presentations about their labs, products and facilities are sure to capture the minds and imagination of every patriotic technocrat.

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname>DRDL</itemname>
                <one>No one understands the Indian Defence Better</one>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/exhibitions/newv13/drdl.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename> DRDL </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/exhibitions/exhibitions/drdo_cover.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
DEFENCE RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ORGANISATION

Pragyan '13 brings you an exclusive sneak peek into the elite Indian arsenal, with an array of Exhibitions by Defence Research and Development Organization, India. Headquartered in New Delhi, DRDO has a network of 51 laboratories which are deeply engaged in developing technology related to aeronautics, armaments, electronics, combat vehicles, engineering systems, missiles, advanced computing and simulation, special materials, naval systems, information systems and agriculture. The organization is supported by more than 5,000 scientists and about 25,000 other scientific, technical and supporting personnel. Tasked with lengthening and strengthening India’s‘stick’, to be wielded for preserving peace, DRDO has made tremendous progress in the development of missiles, weapons, tanks, light combat aircraft, radars, electronic warfare systems etc.


DRDL

Defence Research and Development Laboratory, Hyderabad is a multi-disciplinary Missile System laboratory of DRDO with thrust on design, development and flight evaluation of various types of Missile Systems for armed forces. Right form conceptualization of the weapon system to production and induction into services, the laboratory has capabilities and the state of art infrastructure in terms of facilities and human resource.

The laboratory is also ISO 9001: 2000 Certified for the high International Standards set by it. Ever since its inception as a Special Weapon Development Team (SWDT) in 1958 it has been pioneer in the missile development and has played a pivotal role in bolstering our defences.

Come this Pragyan and get a sneak peek in the world of the Indian missiles as DRDL presents itself in Pragyan with scaled models and presentations to give a deeper insight in missile technology. Don’t miss to grab this once in a lifetime opportunity to get a peek into the latest technologies that keep the defence of our nation intact!!!

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname>HAM Radio</itemname>
                <one> Because it's never too kate to learn</one>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/exhibitions/newv13/ham.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename> HAM Radio </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/exhibitions/exhibitions/ham_radio.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
Amateur RADIO

Many of our most satisfying avocations today consist of making something by hand which machines can usually make more quickly and cheaply, and sometimes better. A similar initiative has been taken by the Amateur Radio Society of Tiruchirappalli, to provide technical advice and assistance to amateur radio enthusiasts. The society represents the interests of amateur radio operators before the India government and supports a number of educational programs throughout the country.

Pragyan, in association with the society provides you a hands on experience on the amateur radio and a once in a lifetime opportunity to operate the Straight key yourselves. Expensive wireless equipment will be on display and the team of experts would be glad to answer any of your queries regarding HAM Radio Operation. They will setup their wireless radio unit on the campus premise and try to contact other HAM radio stations around the world.

Amateur radio (also called ham radio) is the use of designated radio frequency spectrum for purposes of private recreation, non-commercial exchange of messages, wireless experimentation, self-training, and emergency communication. The term "amateur" is used to specify persons interested in radio technique solely with a personal aim and without direct pecuniary interest, and to differentiate it from commercial broadcasting, public safety (such as police and fire), or professional two-way radio services (such as maritime, aviation, taxis, etc.).

A straight key is the common telegraph key as seen in various movies. It is a general term for any switching device used primarily to send Morse code, a method of transmitting text information as a series of on-off tones, lights, or clicks that can be directly understood by a skilled listener or observer without special equipment. Similar keys are used for all forms of manual telegraphy, such as in electrical telegraph and radio telegraphy. Straight keys have been made in numerous variations for over 150 years and in numerous countries. They are the subject of an avid community of key collectors.

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname>Augmented Reality</itemname>
                <one> Step into the Unreal World to unlock the Real You!</one>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/exhibitions/newv13/aug.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename> Augmented Reality </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/exhibitions/exhibitions/aug_3.png</pgimg>
                  <content>

Video games have been entertaining us for nearly 30 years, ever since Pong as introduced to arcades in the early 1970s. Computer graphics have become much more sophisticated since then, and game graphics are pushing the barriers of photorealism.

Now, researchers and engineers are pulling graphics out of your Television screen or computer display and integrating them into real-world environments. This new technology, called AUGMENTED REALITY, blurs the line between what's real and what's computer-generated by enhancing what we see, hear, feel and smell. Augmented reality is changing the way we view the world or at least the way its users see the world. Picture yourself walking or driving down the street.

GAMOOZ India, a software start-up based in the Millennium city of Gurgaon, India is committed to the amazing world of Augmented Reality. This Pragyan, GAMOOZ India comes with a no. of applications and products ready to leave you awestruck in the midst of the glorifying world of technology. Don’t miss a once in a lifetime opportunity of a hands on experience on the apps you wouldn’t have imagined to be existing.

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
            </children>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Sangam</itemname>
            <one>Sangam</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/sangam.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename>Sangam</pagename>
              <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/exhibitions/sangam/sangam.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>

Pragyan is not just a showcase of what the world of technology has to offer us nor is it about intense competitions, mind boggling lectures and enlightening workshops. It also encourages the students to apply their basics that they have learnt and to think out of the box.

Come 2013 and we bring to you an exclusive initiative that not only encourages the top brains of India to churn out fresh ideas and innovations but also enables them to move from conceptualization to implementation. Welcome to SANGAM, a forum for exchange of knowledge between participants, peer students, academicians, technocrats, industrialists and corporates.

For further details, visit Sangam FB

Note: Sangam is only for NIT-T students.

Contacts:
Sagar Arora                                      Nagarajan Sanjay
+91 95438 96104                                  +91 98409 42896

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/exhi.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname> Crossfire</itemname>
        <one>I argue, therefore I am</one>
		<starttime>02-03-2013 16:30</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 17:30</endtime>

        <page>
          <pagename>Crossfire</pagename>
          <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/crossfire/crossfire.jpg</pgimg>
          <content>
Six panellists, One stage, Clash of the wits!
 
It's that time of year again when arguments become flaming arrows amidst a battle of ideas. Each
arrow has a target and it is sure to hit its mark. The archers don’t need much target practice and
they have got ample ammo in grey matter. Pragyan once again brings to you its mind sparking panel
discussion - Crossfire, the hotspot for ideas in February…
 
As with the last years, the event promises to bring together eminent public speakers, from various
walks of life, to the forum of issues. There are issues aplenty around us; from power shortages to
possibilities of another recession to maybe the apocalypse come 2012. The issues get resolved when
the ideas begin to flow. Crossfire promises to turn on the light bulb and churn solutions.
Our previous guests include Prof. Anil Gupta, Dr. P.V. Indiresan, Dr. Sujatha Ramadorai, Mr. Krish
Ashok, Dr. L.S. Ganesh and Cr. Ramesh Jain.

</content>
        </page>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/wishberry.jpg</imgurl>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/crossfire.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Workshops</itemname>
        <one>Learning to do, doing to learn</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Tall Structure Design</itemname>
            <one>Tall Structure Design</one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 13:00</endtime>


<starttime>01-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 <starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 13:00</endtime>


<starttime>02-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
  <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 13:00</endtime>


<starttime>03-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 18:00</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/civil.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
Bolstered by technology, architects have blurred the lines between heaven and earth with lofty sky scrapers! You do realise each of those is a marvel in itself. Having accustomed to bleak landscapes,   skylines lined with towering structures leaves most of us flabbergasted! This CAD based Tall Buildings workshop elucidates the fine concepts of building design, industrial practices, FEM analysis and much more! Structured as an interactive package, you also get to discuss the industrial problems at hand with IIT alumni, get career guidance and interview tips!

It gets even better with practical sessions in CAD modelling and live demonstrations of solutions to problems of the past.

Be prepared to rack your brains!!

For registration details and FAQ, please visit http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/workshop/civil/.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Course Details </pagename>
              <content>
The workshop has the following modules:

Session 1:

Introduction to tall building systems and cover the core concepts involved in "design of tall buildings". Various case studies on present day existing tall buildings are discussed.

Session 2:

It will be a practical session where each participant will design their own CAD model of a tall building and do its analysis.

The following topics will be covered in this workshop:

    - Introduction to tall building systems

    - Theory of load resisting systems

    - Industrial approach projects

    - Site office coordination case studies

    - Modeling. Analysis and Design issues arising during practical sessions

    - Live Demonstration and practical examples
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Workshop Details </pagename>
              <content>
Duration: 1 day (~8 hours)

Date: 1st, 2nd and 3rd March, 2013

Organisers: Civil Simplified

Cost: Rs. 900/- per participant

</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Sugirtha
+91 88706 11839

Ajinkya Khedk
+91 94860 64813

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Automotive Systems and Advancements</itemname>
            <one>Automotive Systems and Advancement</one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 18:00</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/auto.jpg </imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
Any mechanical engineer's true passion would be automobiles. Who wouldn't like to know the impetus behind a 700HP Lambhorgini Avantador LP700-4 Toadster zipping past you! Though that's a rarity in India, we have Auto Next, a consortium of renowned personalities, scientists, reaserarchers and prominent industrialists , candid enough to hold a workshop for us on basics of automotive parts with emphasis on upcoming trends in TATA Motors passenger cars and a practical session demonstrating various parts and assemblies. This could be a brilliant head start in realizing your dream in the automobile industry!
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Course Details </pagename>
              <content>
The workshop comprises of two sessions:
 
Theoretical session:
 
1. Introduction to automobiles
2. Introduction to TATA passenger cars and competitors
3. Advanced braking system
4. Latest technologies and advancements of upcoming and recent Tata Motors passenger cars 
5. Study of under body parts-location and interconnectivity
 
Practical session:
 
Parts study on following automotive parts:
 
1. Engine assembly
2. Clutch assembly
3. Gear assembly
4. Carburettor system
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Workshop Details </pagename>
              <content>
Duration	  : 	1 day(~8 hours)
Day	  :	1st,2nd and 3rd March, 2013
Organisers	  :	AUTO NEXT
Cost	  :  	Rs 700/- per participant
 
*The entire workshop will be conducted by "TATA MOTORS AUTHORISED TRAINING CONSULTANT".
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Parikshit
+91 74182 59519
</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Android Development</itemname>
            <one>Android Development</one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 			<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 13:00</endtime>
 			<starttime>02-03-2013 14:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 			<starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/android.jpg </imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
All your ubiquitous smartphone apps are no longer a perplexity! Learn the jargon of app developers and pitch in to don the creative world of android apps. Pragyan'13 presents you Android App Development workshop for both beginners and pros. You know, more than a hobby it's a great business for the ever burgeoning app market! 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Course Details </pagename>
              <content>
Android Basic
 
•         Introduction to Open Source
•         Introduction to Android technology
•         Structure of Android applications
•         Understanding Manifest
•         Working with Activities
 
o Creating Skelton Application
o Using XML based layouts
o Using Basic Widgets
o Working with Containers
o Using Selection Widgets
o Using Fancy Widgets and Containers
o Applying Menus and Fonts
o Embedding the WebKit browser
o Showing Pop-up Messages
o Dealing with Threads
o Handling Activity Lifecycle events
 
•        Data stores, Network services and APIs
 
o Setting Preferences
o Accessing the Files
o Working with Resources
o Managing Local Databases
o Communicating with Internet
 
•        Intents
 
o Create Intent Filters
o Launching Activities
o Intospection with action
o Handling Rotation
 
•        Content Provides and services
o Using a Content Provider
o Creating a Content Provider
o Managing Permissions
o Creating and Using the Services
o Creating Alerts with Notifications
•        Telephony and SMS
•        Audio, Video and using the Camera
•        Android Hacks
 
 
Every Topic will be discussed using a practical Project.
 
Advanced Level
 
Location and Location Manager:
 
1. Using Location Manager
2. Obtaining the Current Location
3. Displaying a Location Address
4. Location Listeners
5. Using Criteria
6. Notification Alert for Location
 
Telephony Manager:
1. GSMCellLocation
2. GSM Cell ID
3. Obtaining Device ID (IMEI,Android Device ID)
4. Obtaining Software Version
5. Obtaining Line Number
6. Obtaining Country ISO
7. Obtaining Operator name
8. Obtaining Network Operator
9. Obtaining Network Type
10. Obtaining Phone Type
11. Obtaining SIM Country ISO
12. Obtaining SIM Operator
13. Obtaining SIM Operator name
14. Obtaining SIM Serial Number
15. Obtaining SIM State
16. Obtaining Voice mail alpha tag
17. Obtaining voice mail number
 
GPS Enabled Services:
 
1. Enabling GPS
2. Disabling GPS
 
MapView:
 
1. MapActivity
2. Creating MapActivity
3. Adding Overlayitems
4. List Overlay
5. ItemizedOverlay
6. GeoPoint
7. MapController
8. Projection
9. Saving MapView image in SDCard
10. Finding Distance between two point
11. Marking Line between two point
12. Using tap on location
 
GeoCoding and Reverse GeoCoding:
 
1. GeoCoder
2. List  Address
3. Longitude and Latitude
4. Obtaing address from Longitude and Latitude
5. Obtaining Longitude,Latitude from given address
 
SMS Service in Android:
 
1. SMSManager
2. Divide Massage
3. Send Data Message
4. Send Multipart Text Message
5. Send Text Message
 
Project:
 
1. Building “I am Fine Application”
 
I am Fine: GPS Tracking application that keeps your family and friends safe by tracking their real-time location using any Android Phone. With the best in GPS technology, this app tracks the exact location of your family members and alerts you when they are in trouble, using the app's innovative check-in feature.
Track your family using GPS The app allows family members to locate each other on our mobile map. Parents today are busier than ever so you can use our mobile app to track your child whether you're at 
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Workshop Details </pagename>
              <content>

Basic
 
Duration	 :         	 1.5 days (12 hours)
Dates	 :	 1st and 2nd March, 2013
Cost	 :	 600 /- per person

Advanced
 
Duration	 :         	 1.5 days (12 hours)
Dates	 :	 2nd and 3rd March, 2013
Cost	 :	 600 /- per person

 
Basic + Advanced
 
Duration	 :         	 3 days (24 hours)
Dates	 :	 1st, 2nd and 3rd March, 2013
Cost	 :           	 1100 /- per person
 
 
Organisers	 :	RoboTech Labs
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Navneet
+91 77084 06958 
Pratyush
+91 90423 42874
</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Underwater robotics</itemname>
            <one>Underwater robotics</one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 <starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/underwater.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
Not long ago Steven Speilberg plummeted to the depths of the pacific to experience firsthand the wonders of the ocean floor. What if you could stay within the safe confines of your cubicle and yet accomplish such an incredible feat! Come Pragyan get to see robotic enthusiasts manoeuvre their dextrous bots underwater. A robot is only as intelligent as its maker, so grab the opportunity to rub shoulders with the elite community of robotic engineers and learn the amazing funda behind these brilliant technologies. And you don’t just stop with that, you get hands on experience and get to build your own robot!
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Course Details </pagename>
              <content>
In a span of two days the participants will learn,
 
1.    Underwater Robotics - Basics and why is it different?
 
2.    Manoeuvring of Underwater/Surface water vehicles
 
3.    Understanding the underwater Sensing System
 
4.    Fabrication of a Remotely Operated Vehicle (ROV) using the kit provided
 
5.    Application of sensors to develop different kind of abilities for vehicles
 
6.    Modelling of System
 
7.    Control and Navigation
 
8.    The Development on the kit and the testing in the tank
 
Details on Hands On session :
 
1.    Survey Mission: The ROV will be sent on mission to see the manoeuvrability of vehicle.
 
2.    Depth Control of Vehicle. Understanding the controller, sensor feedback, and system itself to develop depth controller.
 
3.    Remotely operated vehicle (ROV) - open loop control.
 
Workshop will contain a Take-away kit with the following contents,
 
                1.    A unique hydrodynamic robot chassis.
 
                2.    Actuators: It will be a thruster made from DC motor.
 
                3.    Controller: a microcontroller kit with thruster drivers, DC-DC converter.
 
                4.    Documentation of workshop.
 
                5.    Codes related to the workshop.
 
Note:You will be provided a very sensitive depth sensor to enable use with meter of depth. But this sensor would not be a take-away.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Workshop Details </pagename>
              <content>
Duration     : 2 days (8 hours each day)
Dates          : 1st and 2nd March,2013 and 
                    2nd and 3rd March, 2013
Organizers  : Robotech Labs
Cost           : 5000/- per team
A team may contain 1-4 members.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Mandakini
+91 91769 22473

Shubham
+91 98432 59583
</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Six Sigma</itemname>
            <one>Six Sigma</one>
						<starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/sixsigma.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
Good management is the art of making problems so interesting and their solutions so constructive that everyone wants to get to work and deal with them!
 
It takes years to become a successful manager. But, let’s not misconstrue years to adding time to your life but rather what you can learn over a short span; as a word from an expert is worth tens of years of experience. Here at Pragyan’13 we usher you through a fast tracked route to become a manager with Six Sigma management workshop! This is sure to impregnate within you the finest concepts of management, hone your leadership skills and change your attitude altogether!
 
Best of all, you can sport a Yellow Belt, one of the premier certifications to demonstrate your managerial prowess!
 
Join the new league of managers!!
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Course Details </pagename>
              <content>
The following is what, will be delivered by Master Black Belt Six Sigma trainers,

• Exposure to Industry Six Sigma Practices
 
• Team Formations
 
• Learn from Industry Expert who handled various Six sigma assignments in OEM’s
 
• Project Handling
 
• Decision Making in Taking Six sigma Tools
 
• Developing Debriefing Skills
 
• Performance Assessments
 
• Live Working Mechanisms


The participants will be provided with a “Yellow Belt” certificate approved by Master Black Belt Six Sigma trainers. The trainers are members of honorary associations like the American Society for Quality. These trainers have gained a tremendous amount of experience from working with some of the leading industries in the world: Alstom, LandT, Schneider Electric, KEC and Honeywell to name a few.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Workshop Details </pagename>
              <content>
Duration         :    2 days (~ 8 hours per day)

Date                :    2nd and 3rd March, 2013

Organisers    :    Experts Hub Training and Consultancy 

Cost                :    Rs.1200/- per Participant
 
The participants will be provided with a “Yellow Belt” certificate approved by Master Black Belt Six Sigma trainers.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Anand
+91 89032 24946 

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Sixth Sense Robotics</itemname>
            <one>Sixth Sense Robotics</one>
			<starttime>01-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 <starttime>02-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 18:00</endtime>
 <starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 18:00</endtime> 
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/sixsense.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
Of all creatures man stands unexampled for his archetypal sixth sense! It's so astute that it replicates itself with technology leading to modern day robots with Artificial Intelligence. With the current pace of advancements, the uber-cool technology of the Terminator, Minority Report or Mr. Tony Stark are not far from reality! You could be at the cusp of this technological leap with our "Sixth Sense Botz" workshop! Join us to learn the interesting techniques of man machine interface, gesture control, image processing, colour recognition and many more.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Course Details </pagename>
              <content>
In the span of two days the participant will learn,
 
1.       Colour recognition application
2.       Ball following robot
3.       Gesture controlled robot
4.       Gesture controlled windows media player
5.       Gesture controlled mouse pointer
6.       Taking images through gestures
7.       Zoom in-out of pictures
 
The course content that will be followed in this workshop will be,
 
1.       Introduction to Arduino
2.       Introduction to Sixth Sense bots
3.       Image processing
·         Introduction
·         Image acquisition devices/sensors
·         Tools used for image processing
4.       Hands On
·         Getting stated with MATLAB
·         Image acquisition in MATLAB
·         Image processing
·         Video acquisition
·         Sending serial and parallel data using MATLAB on Arduino
·         Implementing image processing on kit and robot
 
Workshop will contain a Take-away kit with following contents,
 
1.     Arduino circuit board
2.     USB based webcam(TechCOM brand)
3.     Robot chassis
4.     Wheels
5.     Motors
6.     Castor wheel
7.     Battery(9V), Battery snaps
8.     USB cable for programming
9.     Connecting wires
10.   Screws, Screw driver
11.   Wire cutter/Plier
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Workshop Details </pagename>
              <content>
Duration	  : 	2 days(~8 hours per day)
Day	  :	1st and 2nd March, 2013 and
2nd and 3rd March, 2013
Organisers	  :	ARK Technosolutions
Cost	  :  	Rs 4800/- per team
A team may contain maximum of 4 members.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Arjun
+91 98845 38405

Divya
+91 90032 41862
</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>The Viral Media Workshop</itemname>
            <one>The Viral Media Workshop</one>
			<starttime>03-03-2013 09:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 13:00</endtime>

            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/tvf.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
In today’s world, as data sharing and thought partaking flourishes through YouTube, Twitter and Facebook, fame is imperative. Keeping this concept in mind, The Viral Fever Media Labs, the makers of the hilarious parodies, ‘Rowdies’ and ‘Gaana Wala song’ with 2 million views on Youtube, offer to us, a Workshop explaining the art of making a viral video and the dynamics of its popularity. The Viral Fever is India’s first online TV for Youth, headed by Arunabh Kumar, the Assistant Director of ‘Om Shanthi Om’, an IIT-KGP graduate, who decided to join the entertainment industry, instead of mundane coding on a daily basis. Don’t miss out, as the team guides and entertains you throughout the workshop!
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Course Details </pagename>
              <content>
Session 1 : Concept Development, Direction, Editing

Break        : Practice Video-Making

Session 2 : Viral Online Publicity
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Workshop Details </pagename>
              <content>
Duration	  : 	Half a day(~4 hours) Two Sessions
Day	  :	2nd March, 2013
Organisers	  :	The Viral Fever Media Labs
Cost	  :  	Rs 500/- per head
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Saqib
+91 94896 82283
Priyesh
+91 98400 45954

Or mail to
infotainment@pragyan.org
</content>
            </page>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/workshops.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Pragyan Social Responsibility </itemname>
        <one>Be the change you wish to see</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Disha</itemname>
            <one>Disha</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/disha.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename>Disha</pagename>
              <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/psr/disha/disha.jpg</pgimg>
              <content>
Disha - A career awareness Programme for Engineering Aspirants

Disha is a student awareness programme about the engineering branches and opportunities associated with it, for +1 and +2 students. The whole idea came down with the lack of clarity present among the students regarding what is associated with the branch they choose. The event was coordinated well with departments and team Pragyan where the representatives came up with a presentation about their department.

Disha was conducted on November 4th, 2012 hosted at BHEL in presence of Mrs.Manjula ranghanathan, Divisional railway manager trichy ,General managers of BHEL, Trichy and our beloved director Dr.S.Sundarrajan.  The event kicked off with an interesting talk about “what engineering really is” by master sugavnesh. Representatives who had excelled in their respective departments came forward and put forth their Ideas. This was followed by a discussion between them and the students regarding the curriculum and the various prospects for the students after School.

Specially prepared Handouts about each department were distributed at the end for future reference. The event achieved wat it set out to aim for.
</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Wishberry</itemname>
            <one>Wishberry</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/wishberry.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename>Wishberry</pagename>
              <content>
For details about Wishberry, please visit http://www.wishberry.in/Pragyan-15759.

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/psr.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
      <item>
        <itemname>Outreach</itemname>
        <one>Ruling without boundaries!</one>
        <children>
          <item>
            <itemname>Srishti</itemname>
            <one>Mobile Making Workshop</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/mm_workshop.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> About </pagename>
              <content>
"Embedded Systems" - an intimidating word to comprehend has rather made our lives a lot easier! Embedded systems has a universal presence nowadays, and has made possible the formation of systems with a functionality that cannot be provided in manually operated systems. Mobile phone is one of the most important applications of embedded systems. Once considered a luxury, mobile phones have now become an indispensable part of our daily routine. They have long since entered our personal and office environment and made an indelible mark in the same too.
This Mobile Making Workshop is a microcontroller based basic level workshop which takes you through the process involved in making a mobile phone using AVR microcontroller and some discrete modules from the scratch. By attending this workshop you will not only get to know the interesting process involved in making a mobile phone, but also be able to make one on your own. You are assured to hold a FUNCTIONAL MOBILE PHONE (calling and sending SMS) in your hands using which you can even remotely control a robot! Don't be bogged down by technology - when you break it down, even Rome is just brick and mortar!
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Details </pagename>
              <content>
Workshop Details:

    Date : 15th and 16th December, 2012
    Time : 9 am to 4:30 pm
    Venue : Institute of yoga and consciousness,Yoga village,Beach road,Visakhapatnam
    Organizer : MBS Horizon

Course Details:

    Introduction to Embedded System and Robotics
    Microcontroller Programming
    LCD and Keypad Interfacing
    Communication
    GSM Modem interfacing
    Calling and Sending SMS through GSM modem
    Making of complete mobile using Atmega16, keypad, LCD and GSM modem
    Controlling Robot with mobile

Kit Details:

AVR/8051 Board, GSM Modem, LCD(122x32), Key Pad, USB to Serial cable, FRC cables, Connecting wires, Battery(12V,2A) / 12V/2A DC Adapter

Team Details:

Each team can consist of maximum 4 members and will receive a kit.
Fee: Rs 4800/- per team.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Deepak Krishnan
ws.pragyan@gmail.com
+91 95667 63697

Lakshmi Sandeep Reddy
sandeep@pragyan.org
+91 99525 87249

Sashikant Madana
sashikant@pragyan.org
+91 90427 84902

</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Pragyan Open Quiz</itemname>
            <one>Pragyan Open Quiz</one>
            <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/common13/img/pragyanopenquiz.jpg</imgurl>
            <page>
              <pagename> Introduction </pagename>
              <content>
Back for the second edition, the Pragyan Open Quiz is set to be a meaner package on the whole. The quiz will be conducted by Balls by Picasso, the literary society of NIT-T.
 
The quiz is open to one and all with prizes up for grabs for the best school, college and corporate teams.
 
The total prize money is INR 75,000.
 
It is scheduled to be held on the 27th (Sunday) of January 2013 at Student Activity Center, IIT Madras.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Rules and Regulation </pagename>
              <content>
• Teams can consist of a maximum of 3 members.
 
• No cheating (copying, discussing, googling).
 
• Starred questions will be used to break ties.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Event Format </pagename>
              <content>
Standard quiz with preliminaries followed by a hard-fought quizzing finale.
 
On-spot registrations.
</content>
            </page>
            <page>
              <pagename> Contacts </pagename>
              <content>
Neeraj Sanghvi        
+919566433774
neeraj@pragyan.org

Aanand Mohapatra 
+919884900234
aanand.mohapatra@gmail.com
</content>
            </page>
          </item>
          <item>
            <itemname>Infotainment</itemname>
            <one>Learning was never so much fun</one>
            <children>
              <item>
                <itemname> Fireshow </itemname>
                <one>Informals Fire Show by Thrill Veera</one>
				<starttime>28-02-2013 20:30</starttime>
 <endtime>28-02-2013 21:00</endtime>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/infotainment/newv13/fire.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename> Thrill Veera</pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/infotainment/veera_fire.JPG</pgimg>
                  <content>
     As his name suggests, this artist truly enjoys the thrilling nature of his work, being a connoisseur in the acts of Fire Dancing, combined with Dare Devil type stunts , Ostrich Dance a world record holder for fire breathing. Observe, as both the spirit and the flames of Thrill Veera brighten up darkness in an Infotainment-Informals show after the Pragyan inauguration. 

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname> 3D Projection Mapping </itemname>
                <one>3D Projection Mapping</one>
				<starttime>01-03-2013 19:00</starttime>
 <endtime>01-03-2013 20:00</endtime>

                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/infotainment/newv13/3d.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename>3D Projection Mapping </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/infotainment/3d_mapping_3.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
    Infotainment’13 pushes the usage of Technology technology to new levels this year with 3D projection mapping. Join us on 1st March 2013, at the Ceesat ground for a magnificent spectacle as the Lecture Hall Complex gets transformed to everything from a sky rocket to a pinball machine. Be amazed as the windows and columns pop out into space, and as the structure moves to the beat. The glassless 3D effect is sure to give the watchers an incredibly powerful live experience. We give you an evening full of fun and frolic, as Infotainment sets the stage for everyone to be visually amazed!

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname> Comedy Night Out </itemname>
                <one>TVF Comedy Night Out
H.R (Humour Resources) at Pragyan</one>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/infotainment/newv13/comedy.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename>TVF Comedy Night Out </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/infotainment/tvf_logo.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
TVF Comedy Night Out
By: Vipul Goyal and Deepak Mishra

Time: March 3rd from 7:00 to 9:00 PM
Venue: Barn

Catch Vipul Goyal, Head of H.R (Humour Resources) and Deepak Mishra in this Xtreme Humour session! Featured in The Hindu – Business Line for his talks on Facebook and Sachin Tendulkar, Viral Goyal has the distinction of being the only stand-up comic in India who performs in 4 different languages, English, Hindi, Java and C++.

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname> Robo Dance </itemname>
                <one>Robo Dance by Robo Ganesh</one>
				
<starttime>28-02-2013 19:00</starttime>
 <endtime>28-02-2013 20:00</endtime>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/infotainment/newv13/robo.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename>Robo Dance </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/infotainment/tvf_logo.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
The epitome of flexibility, knowing no limits to the human body, Infotainment’13 presents to you, “Robo” Ganesh! With his popping, sliding and gliding steps, ‘The Mask’  dance etc.he is the winner of the widespread show, "Entertainment Ke Liye Kuch Bhi Karega", and also one of the finalists of the popular series “India’s Got Talent”, assuring an enthralling performance to astonish us all towards the end of the Pragyan inaugural function. 

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname> Rowdies Interviews </itemname>
                <one>The viral fever
Do You have the Rowdy in You!? </one>
<starttime>03-03-2013 19:00</starttime>
 <endtime>03-03-2013 22:00</endtime>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/infotainment/newv13/tvf_info.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename>TVF Rowdies Interviews </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/infotainment/rowdies_photo.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
TVF Rowdies Interviews

By Deepak Mishra and Vipul Goyal
Time: March 3rd from 11:00 AM to 2:00 PM (On-Spot Registration)
Venue: Barn Hall

Test Your Interviewing skills at this INTENSE Stress Interview taken by Deepak Mishra who played Raghu in the spoof, ROWDIES made on the hit MTv show Roadies.

Do You have the Rowdy in You!?

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname> Thaalavattam Band </itemname>
                <one>Thaalavattam Band</one>
				<starttime>02-03-2013 22:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 23:00</endtime>
                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/infotainment/newv13/thava.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename>Thaalavattam </pagename>
                  <pgimg>http://www.pragyan.org/13/home/infotainment/thaalavattam_2.jpg</pgimg>
                  <content>
Thaalavattam is a percussion project that performs and creates drum circles with music instruments made from recycle and up cycled materials. The instruments which are specially designed by Montry Manuel include the likes of his full-fledged pitch perfect drum kit made from paint buckets, didgeridoos made from PVC pipes, shakers from PET bottles and more. Another eminent member of the Thaalavattam, who is often seen meditatively playing his Didgeridoo, is Mehdi Dehbandi. He does not just play the didgeridoo; he crafts them along with his flutes and other such wind instruments. Mehdi hails from Iran and has spent a while in India honing his creativity and giving shape to it through wood, leather, junk and music. 

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
              <item>
                <itemname> PGT Shows </itemname>
                <one>The best of Live Stage Entertainment and Animation</one>
				<starttime>02-03-2013 18:00</starttime>
 <endtime>02-03-2013 20:00</endtime>

                <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/infotainment/newv13/pgt_info.jpg</imgurl>
                <page>
                  <pagename>PGT Shows </pagename>
                  <content>
Pragyan's Got Talent
 
Pragyan’13 presents its first ever platform to flaunt the hidden creativity-imbibed talents within each one of us, offering an impressive show to participants and observers alike. A chance, to unleash all artistic talents that will completely leave everyone totally enthralled.
 
With music, dance, acrobatics, freestyle football, animation, beat boxing, glue art, juggling, magic, mimicry, etc competing on a single platform, and guest appearances by Pradeep Ramesh and the Thaalavattam band, Who do You think would RULE the stage!?
 
Judges Description
 
The panel of judges for Pragyan’s Got Talent includes Montry Manuel of the awe inspiring band Thaalavattam. Thaalavattam is a percussion project that performs and creates drum circles with music instruments made from recycle and up cycled materials. The instruments which are specially designed by Montry Manuel include the likes of his full-fledged pitch perfect drum kit made from paint buckets, didgeridoos made from PVC pipes, shakers from PET bottles and more. Another eminent member of the Thaalavattam, who is often seen meditatively playing his Didgeridoo, is Mehdi Dehbandi. He does not just play the didgeridoo; he crafts them along with his flutes and other such wind instruments. Mehdi hails from Iran and has spent a while in India honing his creativity and giving shape to it through wood, leather, junk and music.
 
Joining these two brilliant performers in the judges’ panel will be another outstanding artist Pradeep Ramesh, from a field which is more of an art than a sport, freelance footballing. He is the current Indian Champion of Freestyle Football and represented India in the World Freestyle Championship, held in Italy in 2012.His eye catchy tricks and stunts will never let you take your eyes off the stage.
 
Joining these legendries will be Vipul Goyal and Deepak Mishra from the well acclaimed The Viral Fever team.

</content>
                </page>
              </item>
            </children>
          </item>
        </children>
        <imgurl>http://www.pragyan.org/13/cms/templates/mainpage/img/mainsite/outreach.jpg</imgurl>
      </item>
    </children>
  </item>
  <item>
    <itemname>What's Now</itemname>
  </item>
  <item>
    <itemname>What's Next</itemname>
  </item>
  <item>
    <itemname>Resources</itemname>
  </item>
</pragyan>